I don't wanna be a product of my environment.
我不想成为环境的产物
I want my environment to be a product of me.
相反，我希望环境为我所左右
Years ago, we had the Church.
很多年前，我们拥有一座教堂
That was only a way of saying we had each other.
那仅是表示我们彼此团结的一种方式
But now, I don't know. It's a funny thing.
但是现在，我不清楚 它很可笑
It put hate in your heart.
它向你心中灌输仇恨
The Knights of Columbus were real head-breakers.
哥伦布骑士是真正的意大利强硬派
They took over their piece of the city.
他们在城市中开辟了自己的地盘
Twenty years after an Irishman couldn't get a fucking job...
20年前，爱尔兰人连工作都找不到
...we had the presidency. May he rest in peace.
现在我们终于迎来了安稳的生活
That's what the niggers don't realize.
这就是那些黑鬼们没有意识到的
If I got one thing against the black chappies, it's this:
如果说我对那些黑鬼有什么成见的话 那就是这个了
No one gives it to you.
没人会施舍给你
You have to take it.
你得自己争取
Vin, don't make me have to come down here again for this.
文，别再让我亲自上门来要钱了
Wort happen again, Mr. C.
不会再有下次的，C先生
Carmers developing into a fine young lady.
卡门已经出落成小美人了
You should be proud.
你应该骄傲
You get your period yet, Carmen?
开始来例假了没，卡门？
You Johnny Sullivars kid?
你是强尼・苏利文的儿子？
- You live with your grandmother? - Yeah.
- 你和你奶奶一起住？ - 对
Vin, get him a couple loaves of bread, couple half-gallons of milk.
文，给他拿些面包和牛奶
Do you like bologna and cheese? Give him some cold cuts.
你喜欢腊肠和奶酪吗？ 再来点冷盘
Throw some mayo in. You like comic books?
还有蛋黄酱 喜欢看漫画书吗？
You do good in school?
你学习好吗？
- Yeah. - That's good. I did too.
- 还行 - 不错，我以前也是
They call that a paradox.
他们说这点和我本人自相矛盾
Just keep it. Buy yourself some makeup.
不用找了，给你自己买点化妆品吧
You ever wanna earn a little extra money, you come by L Street.
要是想赚零花钱的话 就到L街来找我
You know where I am on L Street?
你知道在我在L街的哪里？
Good.
很好
- Good boy. - Thanks.
- 乖孩子 - 谢谢
To you, O Lord, we commend the soul of Alphonsus, your servant.
主啊，您忠实的仆人
In the sight of this world, he is now dead.
在这个世界已经不复存在
Forgive whatever sins he committed through human weakness.
请饶恕他因人性弱点而犯下的罪过
- Amen. - The Church wants you in your place.
- 阿门 - 教会要你听话
Kneel, stand, kneel, stand.
说站就站，说跪就跪
If you go for that sort of thing, I don't know what to do for you.
如果你想干这种事 我不知道还为你做什么
A man makes his own way.
路都是自己走出来的
No one gives it to you.
没人会施舍给你
You have to take it.
你得自己争取
- James Joyce. - Smart, Colin.
- - 这是詹姆士・乔伊斯（著名作家）说的 - 聪明，科林
Guineas from the North End, down Providence...
如果普罗维登斯的意大利佬
...tried to tell me what to do.
跑到这来对我指手画脚
And something maybe happened to them.
那他们就有麻烦了
Maybe like that:
也许，就像那样
Jeez. She fell funny.
天，她倒下的姿势可真可笑
Francis, you really should see somebody.
弗兰克，你应该去看看心理医生了
When you decide to be something, you can be it.
一旦你树立了目标，你就能实现
That's what they don't tell you in the Church.
这个教会没有教你的
When I was your age, they would say we could become cops or criminals.
我像你这么大的时候，他们说 我们可能成为警察或者罪犯
Today what I'm saying to you is this:
今天，我要对你这么说
When you're facing a loaded gun...
当你面对着一把上了膛的枪时
...what's the difference?
这两者又有什么区别呢？
That's my boy.
乖孩子
Terminal ballistics is the study of a projectile...
弹道学是研究发射体
...as it hits a target and the destruction that it causes.
以及击中目标后对其所造成破坏的学科
Take, for instance, what you carry, 9 mm hollow-point.
以你们的佩枪为例，9毫米空尖弹
When the hollow-point hits the skull, what happens is it mushrooms.
当空尖弹击中头骨时 它会爆炸
When it mushrooms it peels back. So you may have six, eight...
爆炸时弹片剥落 你可能会遇到6个，8个或10个
...ten little particles of the bullet that are like razor blades...
像刀片一样的子弹残粒
Sir, yes, sir!
是的，长官
- Tearing their internal organs, their liver, their lungs, their heart...
撕裂他们的内脏 肝，肺，心脏
...bringing tissue, bone, blood, brain matter, and that's called a blowback.
内部组织，血液，大脑 …这就叫气体反冲
Fuck you. Fucking queers.
去你妈的，一帮娘们
Firemen getting pussy for the first time in the history of fire or pussy.
消防员第一次面对大火或女人时很逊
Hey, go save a kitten in a tree, you fucking homos.
嗨，快回去救困在树上的猫吧 你们这些混蛋同性恋
Pencils.
铅笔准备好
Begin.
开始
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
Forget it.
别想了
Your father was a janitor, his sors only a cop.
老爸是看大门的 儿子就只有当警察的命
Those fucking firefighters are a bunch of homos.
那帮他妈的消防员都是同性恋
They are.
确实
So she tells me, "You never finish anything. You finish the police course...
她对我说，你从来没完成过任何事 等你完成了警校的课程
...you get taken care of again, baby." So after graduation, I get a blowjob again.
我就再和你好，宝贝 等毕业了，她就又给我爽了
That's great. Your mother must be a wonderful woman.
不错啊了，你妈一定是个了不起的女人
Fuck yourself.
去你的
Put it this way. You're a black guy in Boston.
这么说吧，你是波士顿黑人
You don't need any help from me to be completely fucked.
不需要我动手就有人来整你了
The Massachusetts State Police has a long tradition of excellence.
麻萨诸塞州警察拥有悠久的良好声誉
Your graduation today solidifies your acceptance...
今天你们在此毕业
...into one of the finest law enforcement agencies in our nation.
即将成为我们国家优秀的警务人员
As the governor of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, I am confident...
做为马萨诸塞州警务主管
...each and every one of you will serve with distinction, honor and integrity.
我坚信，你们每一个人 都将出色，荣耀，诚实地效忠国家
Congratulations to all our new troopers.
祝贺大家
Thank you. You are dismissed.
谢谢，你们可以解散了
Sullivan, assigned to plainclothes right out of the gate, congratulations.
苏利文，你刚毕业就是便衣 祝贺你
- We're going for a beer. You wanna come? - No, I'll catch up with you guys.
- 我们要去喝一杯，一起来吗？ - 不了，我一会去找你们
School's out.
再也不用上学了
Thank you, Frank.
弗兰克，谢谢
You earned it.
你应得的
No more pencils, no more books.
不用再念书了
All right.
好
This is not the regular police...
这里不是普通的警队
...this is the state police. - And fire!
- …是州立警队 - 开枪！
Your training will illustrate the difference.
你们的训练会证明有什么不同
State police, search warrant! State police, open the door!
州警察，有搜查证！ 州警察，开门！
What's the difference?
有什么不同？
- Go, go, go! - Sir, yes, sir!
- 上！上！ - 是的，长官！
- Is that understood?
- 明白！
Move it, get the fuck down right now. Get down, right now.
给我趴下！快趴下！
Congratulations on passing the detective's exam, and welcome...
恭喜你通过了警探考核
...to the Special Investigation Unit. - Whoop-de-fucking-do.
…欢迎加入我们特别调查组 - 看你他妈的那德行
We won't be working together, that is, directly.
我们以后不会一起工作，直接地说
You'll be working for Captain Ellerby, but I like to see everybody.
你会跟艾勒文队长 但我希望能看下你们每个人
You're a worker. You rise fast.
只要你努力，就会很快升职的
Like a 12-year-old's dick.
就像十二岁孩子的阳具
- Thank you, sergeant. - My pleasure.
- 谢谢警官 - 不客气
- Thank you, sir. - Good luck.
- 谢谢长官 - 祝你好运
- Congratulations. - Thanks, hon.
- 祝贺你 - 谢谢，亲爱的
You can go in there now.
你现在可以进去了
You can sit.
请坐
So...
嗯…
Do you know what we do here? My section?
你知道我们是做什么的吗？ 我这个部门？
- Yes, sir, I have an idea... - Let's say you have no idea...
- 是的，长官，我知道… - 你根本什么都不知道…
...and leave it at that, okay?
懂吗？什么都不知道
No idea. Zip. None.
不知道
If you had an idea what we do, we would not be good at what we do, would we?
如果你知道我们是做什么的 那就说明我们做的不好，是不是？
We would be cunts.
那我们就成狗屁了
Are you calling us cunts?
你是不是叫我们狗屁？
Staff Sergeant Dignam has a style of his own.
迪克曼警官有他自己的处事风格
I'm afraid we all have to get used to it.
恐怕我们都得去适应
So you have family connections down in Southie, right? Through your father?
你家和南波士顿的黑帮有关系，对吧？ 通过你父亲？
Why don't you tell us about your Uncle Jackie?
和我们说说你叔叔杰西吧
He was a carpet layer for Jordan Marsh.
他是乔治・马沙的手下
Uncle Jackie was a small-time bookie who tended bar at the Vets in Somerville.
他只不过是个三流管帐而已 在萨默维尔管个小酒吧
He got popped by Nicastro in '95. We found his body out by the airport.
他95年被人干掉了 我们在机场里发现了他的尸体
That's right.
没错
- I remember his funeral. - Oh, good.
- 我还记得他的葬礼 - 不错
Closed casket?
棺材是盖着的吧？
That's right.
没错
So tell anybody up at Deerfield...
告诉大家在你因为用椅子 痛打一个体育老师
Before you got kicked out for whaling on a gym teacher with a chair.
被开除之前你在预科学校的事
- You had an uncle met his demise like that?
你叔叔就像那样挂掉的？
I got a question.
我有个问题
How fucked up are you?
你这人到底多衰？
Hi, Darlene.
嗨，亲爱的
What you got, staff sergeant? In no time you made sergeant.
有什么好消息吗，参谋警官？ 用不了多久你就能当上警官了
- SIU. What a country. - Perfect.
- 特别调查组，很牛吧 - 太好了
Hey, I don't mind going it alone.
我不介意一个人独闯
You know, if you went alone once in a while you might get somewhere.
如果你偶尔也独闯的话 可能有机会出头
We're cops, all right? This isn't somewhere.
我们是警察，这不是出人投地
All right, lookit, I know you're a worker. Maybe I can do something for you.
我知道你很努力，也许我能帮你一把
You got any suits, or do you like...
你家里有没有西装？
...coming to work dressed like you're gonna invade Poland?
还是你就喜欢 穿得跟要进攻波兰一样
You got quite the family tree. That maggot uncle of yours...
小子，你家族可不简单啊 你另一个叔叔
...Tommy Costigan, is another goof. He gets busted selling guns...
汤米・科斯提根也是个傻子，他因为…
...to federal officers, among many, many, many other departures...
贩卖枪支给联邦警察而被捕 这只是他众多傻事中的一件
...from our normative behavior. - And what's this got to do with me?
这些和我有什么关系？
Why are you pretending to be a cop?
为什么你要假装做警察？
This unit is new, and you are the newest members of it.
这是个新部门，你们也都是新人
You have been selected for it on the basis of intelligence and aptitude.
你们都是我们精选出来的人才
This is an elite unit.
这是精英部门
Our job is to smash or marginally disrupt...
我们的工作就是粉碎 或者说小规模地折腾一下
...organized crime in this city...
城里有组织的犯罪团体
...by enanced cooperation with the FBI...
我们与联邦调查局的紧密合作
...represented here today by Agent Frank Lazio.
弗兰克・拉齐奥探员是他们的代表
And we will do it.
我们会做到的
And by organized crime in this city, you know who we mean.
城里有组织的犯罪团体 你们知道我们指的是谁
That's Jackie Costigan. That's an old picture.
杰西・科斯提根，这张是他的旧照
Jackie met his demise.
杰西已经死了
Last known photograph.
最后的遗照
Costello uses three key guys.
卡斯特罗手下有3员大将
That's Fitzy. Off-the-boat psycho, lives in Brockton with his mother.
菲兹，疯子移民 和他妈一起住在德拉大街上
She's straight out of Going My Way.
她也有点疯
Delahunt, muscle.
德拉亨特，外号肌肉男
French, the number one. But of course, the rock star, you-know-who.
法国佬，他的头号大将 当然，还有你们都知道的我们的头号明星
We've done a briefing book, so read up. I want all ideas...
我们已经作了一份简报 读一读，有任何提议就告诉我
...so I can pass them off as my own.
这样我才可以拿去自己邀功
Work hard, you'll rise fast. You're in the best possible position...
只要你们好好干，就会很快升迁的
...in the department. Let's go to work.
现在就是你们最好的机会 开始干活吧
Your old man was a fucking hump from Southie.
你老爸在南波士顿卖苦力
Baggage handler at the airport, right?
机场的行李搬运工，是吧？
Family's all criminals except for the old man, huh?
除了你老爸，你家其他人都是罪犯吧？
And one priest, since you seem to know everything.
还有个牧师呢 看上去你无所不知呢
Last I heard he was married to a 12-year-old boy, living on a beach in Thailand.
我还听说他和一个12岁的小男孩结了婚 一起住在泰国的海滨呢
Fucking family's dug into the Southie projects like ticks.
你们一家像虱子一样扎根在南波士顿
Three-decker men at best. You, however, grew up...
最多住着三层房子 而你…
...on the North Shore, huh? Well, la-di-fucking-da.
却在北岸长大，对吗？ 真他妈的
You were kind of a double kid, I bet, right?
你是个有双重性格的小子吧？
One kid with your old man, one kid with your mother.
和你老爸在一起时一个样 和你老妈在一起时另一个样
You're upper-middle class during the weeks, then you're hanging...
你平时以中产阶级自居，到了周末
...in the Southie projects with your daddy, the fucking donkey...
而到周末就跑到南岸你老爸那去
...on the weekends. I got that right?
我说得没错吧
Yup. You have different accents?
你有不同的口音吧？
You did, didn't you, you little fucking snake?
你有，是不是？你他妈这个小骗子
- You were like different people. - You a psychiatrist?
- 你就是两面派 - 你是精神分析师？
If I was, I'd ask you why you're a statie making 30 grand a year.
如果我是的话 我会问你为何甘愿做州警领这区区3万元
And I think if I was Sigmund fucking Freud I wouldn't get an answer.
就算我他妈是弗洛伊德的话 我也不知道答案
Tell me, what's a lace-curtain motherfucker like you doing in the staties?
你告诉我，像你这样的混蛋 在州警队里干什么？
Well, families are always rising or falling in America, am I right?
美国家庭总是起起落落，对吗？
- Who said that? - Hawthorne.
这话是谁说的？ - 霍桑
What's the matter, smart-ass, you don't know any fucking Shakespeare?
你他妈怎么了 就不会说点莎士比亚的吗？
We have a question.
我们有个问题
Do you wanna be a cop, or do you wanna appear to be a cop?
你是真想做警察 还是想看上去像个警察
It's an honest question.
希望你能诚实回答
Lot of guys want to appear to be cops. Gun, badge, pretend they're on TV.
很多人只是觉得当警察很酷 佩枪，警徽，像电视上一样
A lot of them just wanna slam a nigger through a window...
很多人只是想找个借口教训黑鬼
I'm set without your own personal job application, sergeant.
我听够了你那些个人工作的狗屁话
- What did you say? - Sir, what do you want from me?
- 你说什么？小子 - 你们到底想让我干什么？
Hey, he can't help you.
嗨，混蛋，他帮不了你
I know what you are. I know what you are...
我知道你是什么人 我知道你是什么人…
...and I know what you're not.
我也知道你不是什么人
I'm the best friend you have and I'm gonna help you understand something.
我是最了解你的人 而且我要告诉你，混蛋
You're no fucking cop.
你不是他妈的警察！
He's right. We deal in deception here.
他说的没错 我们这里调查的是外面那些人
What we do not deal with is self-deception.
而不是自己人的欺诈行为
Five years from now you could be anything else in the world.
从现在起5年内，你可以成为任何人
But you will not be a Massachusetts state trooper.
但你不会成为马萨诸塞州警员
- Are you sure of that? - I'm sure of that.
- 你确定吗？ - 我确定
Guaran-fucking-teed.
我他妈的保证
You had 1400 on your SATs, kid. You're an astronaut, not a statie.
你大学入学考试得了1400分 这分够当宇航员的了，还当什么警察
You don't have much family.
你没有什么家人了
I don't have any family.
- 我没有任何家人
What's this I hear from Stephanie about you becoming a policeman?
听斯蒂芬尼说你要当上警察了 这是怎么回事？
Stephanie, who was the only one who came to my father's funeral?
你说的是那个唯一来参加 我爸葬礼的？
- That Stephanie? - Yeah, that Stephanie.
- 那个斯蒂芬尼？ - 对，那个斯蒂芬尼
- Nothing much to it, Uncle Edward. - Trying to prove something to the family?
- 没什么好说的，爱德华叔叔 - 你想证明什么给你家人看吗？
When you say "the family," who do you mean exactly? You?
你说家人，你指的是谁？你吗？
You always have to question everything, don't you?
你总是要置疑一切，是吗？
Maybe it would've done you some good to have some questions from time to time.
也许时不时地问自己一些问题对你有好处
"Am I an asshole? Are my kids a mess?
我是混蛋吗？我的孩子很糟糕吗？
Is my wife a money-grubbing whore?" I mean, those are questions, right?
我老婆是不是个贪财的婊子？ 这些都是问题，对吧？
"Have I ever been good to my dying sister, or am I just now pretending to be?"
我是否好好对待过我垂死的姐姐？ 还是我现在只是假装这样？
Do you need some money for the funeral?
你需要钱准备葬礼吗？
When my mother dies, we don't have any more connection.
我妈妈去世后，我们就再无瓜葛
It's lovely. You get the high ceilings, the parquet floors. Bathroom is massive.
这房子很漂亮，天花板很高 木地板，浴室也很大
The fridge has got an alarm in it in case you have...
冰箱上有警报器
...eating issues, which is a joke. Not a very funny one.
以防你吃饭噎着 开玩笑的…其实不是很好笑
Well, there's a great view of the State House. Beacon Hill, you can see it.
这里看市政厅，灯塔山也是一目了然
I mean, you move in, you're upper-class by about Tuesday.
你要是搬进来的话 马上就能成马萨诸塞州的上流阶级
- So you're a cop. - A state-police detective.
- 那么你是警察了 - 州警探
A state-police detective.
州警探
And are you a married state-police detective?
你是个结了婚的州警探吗？
No.
不是
Because this is kind of a... Sort of a big place and...
这房子…一个人住有点大了
I have a co-signer.
我有合租人
Oh, cool. Yeah, you intend to have a houseguest. That's cool. Good.
那不错，你有客人会来，很好
- Yeah, it's got... - Just give me the papers.
- 嗯… - 把合同给我
Sure.
行
Eternal rest grant unto her, O Lord, and let perpetual light shine upon her.
主啊，请赋予她永恒的安宁 让光明永照其身
- Amen. - May she rest in peace. Amen.
- 阿门 - 愿她安息，阿门
May her soul and the souls of all the faithful departed...
愿她的灵魂籍主的恩慈
...through the mercy of God rest in peace.
永远安息
Amen.
阿门
So what do I do?
要我干什么？
There's money behind this operation. You won't be paid as a regular cop...
这个行动有资金支持 我们不会像普通警察那样付你工资
...but there's a bonus involved.
这里有奖金
Tax-free.
免税的
We can't conceal that you were a trainee. You'll be convicted of a crime.
我们无法隐瞒你曾是警校学员的事实 你要去犯罪
We're thinking a guilty plea to assault and battery would make sense.
我们想有恶性伤人案底的警察 可能会比较可信
Given your nature.
正好符合你的本性
You'll do enough jail time to convince anyone this is no setup.
你要在牢里呆段时间 好叫别人相信这一切都不是圈套
You'll be on probation, see a court-ordered shrink...
之后你会被假释 看法庭指定的心理医生
...the whole nine yards.
做整套戏
You wanna serve the Commonwealth, this is your chance.
你想为国家效力，这是个好机会
We need you, pal.
我们需要你，老兄
You've already pretended to be a Costigan from South Boston.
你已经假装是南波士顿的卡斯提根了
- Every weekend, sergeant. - Perfect.
- 只有每个周末才是，警官 - 好极了
Do it again.
再做一次
For me.
为了我
- Hey, you Billy Costigan? - Yeah, who wants to know?
- 你是比尔・卡斯提根？ - 对，怎么了？
Well, nothing. I know a Sean Costigan down on L Street.
没什么，我认识一个叫肖恩・科斯提根的 他住在L街
- Yeah, that's my cousin. - Connected. Not too bright.
- 那是我表兄 - 我认识他，那家伙很不识相
- Yeah, I know. - I mean, no offense.
- 我知道 - 我并不想冒犯你
- Billy? - Yeah, it's me.
- 比利？ - 对，是我
- Oh, my God. Good to see you. - Aunt Kathy, how are you?
- 我的上帝啊，见到你真好 - 姑妈，你还好吗？
Oh, good to see you. Come on in.
见到你真好啊，快进来
They said you was in the staties. I couldn't believe it.
听说你当上了州警，真是难以置信
I got kicked out, like, four months ago.
我被开除了，好像是我4个月前
Yeah, it was in the papers.
都登报了
So you know.
这么说你知道了
And why are we graced with your presence?
你怎么会大驾光临呢？
I brought your mother some pictures of my father.
我给你妈带了点我爸的照片来
- Look at the smile. - My mother had them. My...
- 看那笑容 - 是我妈保存的
My mother's dead.
我妈…我妈去世了
I'm sorry. Sorry for your troubles.
对不起，真的抱歉
I was at a funeral myself, man.
我也参加了个葬礼
Myles Kennefick. Knew him in school.
迈尔斯・卡内菲克，学校里认识的
He was a young guy, you know? It's terrible. It's a shame.
他还很年轻，真可怕，真可惜
- You remember that. What a night. - Listen.
- 还记得那个晚上吗？真是… - 听着
I got, like...
我拿到…
- Like 30,000 bucks, right? Insurance money. - Yeah.
- 我拿到了大概3万美金的保险金
You know, after my mother passed and everything.
我妈去世的保险金
In your line of work, if I gave you...
在你们这行，如果我…
...like, what, say, 10,000, what could I get back?
如果我给你1万的话，我能赚多少？
You know what you...
你知道…
You know what you usually say at these moments.
你知道我们这种时候通常会说什么吗？
- What? What? - Come on, man.
- 什么？什么？ - 别装了
Oh, come on, you fucking moron. Come on.
我靠，你这个混蛋
What, you want me to say it?
你想听我亲口说？
I'm not a cop, all right?
我不是警察，好吗？
- I'm your fucking cousin. - You're bad.
- 我他妈是你表弟 - 你这坏蛋
You corrupt fuck, man. You must be my cousin.
你被腐蚀了，你一定是我表兄
Fucking Ricans think they know everything.
那帮波多黎各人觉得他们什么都懂
If they knew shit, they wouldn't be Puerto Ricans.
他们要是真懂 就他妈不是波多黎各人了
R is for Ricans P is for pigs
波多黎各猪
Would you shut the fuck up for five seconds, huh?
你他妈就不能闭上会嘴一会？
That's right. You used to be a cop.
没错，你以前是警察
When we're working together just limit it to two eight-balls an hour.
我们在干活，你少吸点行不行？
We're not even supposed to be doing this shit this close to Worcester.
我们不应该在这儿干活 离伍斯特德太近了
This side of Worcester.
就在伍斯特德边上
- Says who? - Says him. Says Costello.
- 谁说的？ - 他说的，卡斯特罗说的
God says, as far as you're...
对你来说…
...concerned.
就当是上帝说的
No, no, he's no cop. He got out of the joint three weeks ago.
不，不，不，他不是警察 他3周前才从牢里放出来
- Cunt cop. - No, no, no.
- 王八蛋警察 - 不，不，不
He talks like his shit don't stink, but he's good people.
他说话不好听，不过他是好人
Well, I knew his father.
我认识他爸
- I liked his Uncle Jackie better. - Jackie was all right.
- 我更喜欢他叔叔杰西 - 杰西还不错
Uncle Jackie was excellent.
杰西叔叔棒极了！
Fucking guineas.
该死的意大利人
- To Jackie. - Uncle Jackie.
- 敬杰西 - 杰西
Cranberry juice.
来杯酸梅汁
It's a natural diuretic.
那是天然利尿剂
My girlfriend drinks it when she's got her period.
我马子来例假时就喝这个
What, do you got your period?
怎么？你也来例假了？
- Fucking...! - Get off!
- 靠！ - 放手！
- Get your fucking hands off me! - Hey. Hey, hey.
- 他妈的把你手拿开！ - 嘿，嘿，嘿
Do you know me?
你知道我是谁吗？
No. No.
不知道
Well, I'm the guy that tells you there are guys you can hit...
我是来告诉你什么人能打…
...and there's guys you can't.
还有什么人不能打的
Now, that's not quite a guy you can't hit...
这人虽说不是一点不能打他
...but it's almost a guy you can't hit.
但你最好还是别打他
So I'm gonna make a fucking ruling on this right now:
我现在就要立个规矩
You don't fucking hit him. You understand?
你他妈不能打他，明白吗？
Yeah, excellent. Fine. Fine, fine.
好吧
I fucking know you. I know your family.
我认识你，我认识你家人
You make one more drug deal...
你要是…
...with that idiot fucking cop-magnet of a cousin of yours...
再跟你那笨蛋表兄卖毒品的话
...and I'll forget your grandmother was so nice to me.
我就忘了你祖母曾经对我有多好
I'll cut your fucking nuts off. You understand that?
我会把你阉了的，明白了吗？
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
明白
What are you drinking?
你喝什么？
A cranberry juice.
酸莓汁
What is it, your period?
怎么了，你来例假了？
Get him a cranberry juice.
给他一杯酸梅汁
Hey, fuckhead, that's Jackie's nephew.
嗨，他是杰西的侄子
What? "Oh," fucking what?
什么？你他妈“哦”什么？
Get the fuck out of here.
离开这吧
Sorry I'm late.
对不起，我迟到了
Staff Sergeant Dignam is our liaison to the undercover section.
这是迪克曼警官 主要负责与卧底的联系
His undercover work is extensive.
对卧底工作非常了解
He's here to give us his report. Sergeant Dignam.
他来给我们做下报告
Okay, my people are out there.
我手下做卧底那几个人
They're like fucking Indians. You're not gonna see them.
就像他妈的印第安人一样
You'll hear about them through me or Captain Queenan.
除了我和昆南长官外 你们不会知道他们的行踪
You will not ever know the identity of undercover people.
你们永远都不会知道卧底的身份
Unfortunately, this shithole has more leaks than the Iraqi navy.
不幸的是，这鬼部门 比伊拉克海军的漏洞还多
- Fuck yourself. - I'm tired from fucking your wife.
- 去死吧 - 我干你老婆都干腻了
- How's your mother? - Tired from fucking my father.
- 你妈好吗？ - 她干我爸都干腻了
Good. Today, girls...
好了，姑娘们
...what I have is microprocessors.
今天我要给你们说的是微处理器
Somebody, as you may already know, stole 20 microprocessors...
你们可能已经听说了
...from the Mass Processor Company out on Route 128.
有人偷了28号公路上 迈斯公司生产的20个微处理器
These are the kind they put into computers...
这种处理器放进电脑中
...that could put a cruise missile up the ass of a camel...
能准确地从几百英里外
...from a couple hundred miles away.
把巡航导弹打进骆驼的屁眼
These pieces of plastic are won'th about 100 grand apiece.
这些塑料小东西要10几万块一个
We got a guy working for the company two months...
有个人在那公司干了2个月
...walks out the door with a box of processors on Tuesday...
结果他周二偷了微处理器
...has a ticket for Florida on Wednesday...
订了周三去佛罗里达的机票
...but on Thursday, he gets found in a Dumpster.
周四他的尸体就在垃圾箱里被发现了
You know where that dirtball started his life?
你知道这家伙在哪长大的？
Southie projects.
南波士顿
- What was his name, the departed? - Myles Kennefick.
- 那死人叫什么名字？ - 迈尔斯・卡内菲克
Got the job with a forged UMass transcript. UMass, Boston...
他靠假马萨诸塞州州立大学文凭 找到这份工作
...which happens to... - South Boston?
…恰好是在… - 南波士顿？
Oh, you're a fucking genius. Who forged your transcript, dickhead?
你真是个天才 你的假文凭是从哪来的，蠢货？
His old man runs the Hibernian Liquor Mart. Kennefick's.
这个人他老爸马特・卡内菲克 不也是爱尔兰帮成员吗？
We're not here to solve the case of the missing scumbag.
我们现在不是要讨论谁偷了微处理器
We're here to nail Costello.
卡斯特罗才是我们的重点
All right, look. We got a guy...
线人报告说
...says Costello's moving the processors to China.
卡斯特罗正准备把处理器卖到中国去
He set up the whole fucking job and popped Kennefick.
他一手策划了这件事 并谋杀迈尔斯・卡内菲克
You do not want to miss it if Costello takes a dump.
我们可不能错过卡斯特罗销赃的事情
We'd miss less if you made your informants available to us and the Bureau.
你要是多给我们情报 我们就能盯的更紧
Without asking for too many details, do you have anyone in with Costello now?
我不想追究细节 现在在卡斯特罗身边有你的卧底吗？
Maybe. Maybe not.
可能有，也可能没有
Maybe fuck yourself.
可能去你妈的
My theory on Feds is they're like mushrooms.
我对卧底的理论就和养蘑菇一样
Feed them shit and keep them in the dark.
喂它们吃屎，把他们留在暗处
You girls have a good day.
姑娘们工作愉快
Normally he's a very nice guy.
这人其实还不错
Don't judge him from this meeting alone.
只是这次会议有点反常
Now, Mrs. Kennefick, I knew your son.
卡内菲克夫人，我认识你儿子
I knew Myles.
我认识迈尔斯
He was younger than me, but he was behind me in school.
他比我小，但是我的学弟
I wanna get these people who did this to him.
我希望能抓到那些害死他的人
Would you like to help us? You wanna help catch the people...
你想帮我吗？
...who forced your son to do a robbery and then killed him?
你想帮我找到那些逼他抢劫 之后又杀了他的人吗？
Allegedly.
据称如此
If he was killed, he probably did something wrong.
如果他是被谋杀的 那他一定做了什么错事
But not the robbery. That's not wrong.
不是说抢劫，那不算错
He did something else wrong?
他还做了其它错事吗？
Wave to your girlfriend, honey.
亲爱的，跟你马子打个招呼
I mean, fuck yourself.
你去死吧
- Did you get that? - "Allegedly" or "fuck yourself"?
- 你记下来了吗？ - “据称如此”还是“你去死吧”？
- Welcome to the neighborhood. - Different breed down here, sarge.
- 长见识了吧 - 这人可真怪啊
I need a cup of coffee.
我要去喝杯咖啡
You making a house call?
你是上门服务吗？
Have I seen you professionally?
我工作上有见过你吗？
No, no. No, I know who you are, though. I know.
不，但我知道你
Guys gotta use their service revolver in the course of duty...
那些在工作中开了枪的人…
...and then they get to come to talk to you about their feelings and whatnot.
都得和你谈谈心，聊聊天
No, no, I know how it goes. You're a mental health professional.
不，不，我真的知道 你是心理健康专家
I have an appointment on this floor.
对，我在这层有个预约…
Oh, well, you'll have fun. They're all frigging crazy on that floor.
你一定会很开心的 这层都是些怪人
- I'm one more up. - Oh, fancy policeman.
- 我还要再上一层 - 噢，警察啊
- Yeah, that's right, fancy. - Are you a statie?
- 是啊 - 你是州警？
Yeah, I am. I'm actually going to law school also.
对，另外我现在还在上法学院
Suffolk, nights?
上夜校吗？
Yeah, they don't run Harvard at night, last time I checked.
是啊，哈佛不开夜校的 我上回查过了
- Whers the last time you checked? - Before I went to fucking Suffolk.
- 你上次是什么时候查的？ - 在我上他妈的夜校之前
Okay, listen, I went to UMass. I wasrt insulting you.
好啦，我是马萨诸塞州州立大学毕业的 我不想开你玩笑
Well, I thought you were. So now you gotta buy me dinner.
我觉得你是呢，所以你得请我吃饭
Maybe you can shoot someone and then see me professionally.
也许你杀个人后 我们就能正式见面了
I'll stab someone in the heart with a fucking ice pick if it gets me dinner with you.
要是能跟你吃上饭 用他妈地冰锥戳人心脏的事我都干
That's all right. I'm a detective. I'll find you.
不用，我是警探 我能找到你的
No, sorry. I'm just joking. I need the card. Card helps.
我开玩笑的，这个我需要 名片有用
Nice to meet you, Madolyn.
很高兴认识你，曼德琳
Hi, Dad. I had no idea about the tail until I saw it.
你好，爸爸 我事先不知道跟踪你的事
No, I couldn't. I had the other guy with me, I couldn't...
我不能，当时还有其它同事在
All right, it's a blue sedan and then a white van.
是一辆蓝色的轿车 还有一辆白色的货车
It's fucked up with graffiti. And the van is the audio surveillance.
货车侧面有涂鸦 上面有声音探测系统
All right, have a nice day.
好的，祝你愉快
Cut him here.
在这甩了他们
Bye-bye.
再见
Jerk-ass!
混蛋！
Come on, Babu. I can't do anymore. I cannot hold off.
巴布，我不能再这么做了
Don't let me go back empty-handed. Don't do this. I wanna help you.
别再让我空手而归，别这样 我只是想帮你
Come to my store next Friday. I'll give you the money.
你下周五过来，我给你钱
This is Friday, Babu. How many times I gotta tell you?
今天就是周五，巴布 我要跟你说多少回？
You keep on calling me Babu. It's Singh, motherfucker.
你一直叫我巴布，我叫辛，混蛋
I'm trying to help you.
我只是想帮你
You keep telling me I'm your friend. You don't even know my fucking name.
你一直说我是你的朋友 但你连我名字都他妈不知道
I'm gonna catch a beating if I go back again like last week.
如果我还想上星期那样回去 我就要挨揍了
See this guy? You see this guy? This guy don't want you to have the money.
看到他了吗？看到这个人了吗？ 他可不想你留着钱
Because he wants to come back there and squash your head.
要是我们再回来，他就会你打爆你的头
I have one customer sitting here. What I'm gonna do?
我这还有一个顾客，你想叫我怎么办？
Business is bad? You opened a store in an Irish neighborhood.
生意好差？你是在爱尔兰区开了这个店
These are dirty people. Don't you know that?
这些人都是狠角色，你不知道吗？
Sell potatoes, I don't know what you're gonna do.
我也不知道你该怎么办
- Excuse me, gentlemen. Excuse me. Sorry. - Know what I'm saying?
- 对不起，伙计们 - 你明白我的意思吗？
You fellas come from Providence?
你们是从普罗维登斯来的吗？
It isn't any of your business, is it, now?
这没你的事
What, are you fucking delivering cannolis or something?
你们是不是送蛋卷的什么的？
Hey! You are killing my business, man!
你在干嘛？这是我的店！
Fuck!
靠！
What's wrong with this fucking country? Everybody hates everybody!
这个国家大家都彼此憎恨吗？
Get out of here. Get out of here!
你给我滚！滚！
- Now, you also do probation work, right? - That's right, I see violent offenders.
- 你也作假释工作吗？ - 是的，我见过暴力犯罪的
The principles of detection tell me these two gentlemen came from Providence.
按照侦查原则 这两个人来自普罗维登斯
Lieutenant Risteen, Lynn PD. I'd appreciate it you get out of my crime scene.
我是波士顿警察局的 请离开我的犯罪现场
Yeah, actually, it's my crime scene, but knock yourself out.
事实上这是我的犯罪现场 你自己好好干吧
Thanks.
谢谢
I saw a dead guy. I think I'm having posttraumatic stress.
我看到了死尸 我想我现在有很大的精神压力
Can I meet you for lunch?
一起吃午饭吗？
All right, see you then.
好的，一会见
Who's the lead detective?
这案子谁负责？
Good. He's a lox.
那好办，那家伙很蠢
Get the cops to look at Jimmy Pappas for the hit. He had nothing to do with it...
带人去吉米・帕斯家查查 当然他和这事没关系
...and he'll say so.
他也会这么说的
Look in his car, you'll find the gun that did it, registered, official. Providence.
你去查他的车，里面有一只枪 那枪注册的是普罗维登斯
In the trunk or the glove compartment?
行礼箱还是前面的工具箱？
Hey, you wanna see some dead guys?
嗨，想见见死人吗？
Hey, this will get Captain Ellerby on the 6:00 news.
这事肯定能让艾勒文队长上晚6点新闻
No wonder you get ahead.
难怪你这么受宠
Have a seat, Bill.
坐吧
Do you know John Lennon?
你知道约翰・列侬吗？
Yeah, sure, he was the president before Lincoln.
他是林肯总统的前任
Lennon said:
列侬说
"I'm an artist.
“我是艺术家
You give me a fucking tuba, I'll get you something out of it."
你他妈给我根管子 我就能吹出首曲子来”
I tell you, Mr. Costello...
告诉你卡斯特罗先生
...I'd like to squeeze some fucking money out of it.
我更想从管子里挤出点钱来花花
Smart-mouth.
好个伶牙俐齿
Too bad.
不过太糟了
If you'll indulge me...
如果你允许我…
Now what?
又去哪？
Choir practice.
唱诗班排练
Choir practice...
唱诗班排练…
The point I'm making with John Lennon is...
我提列侬是要告诉你…
...a man could look at anything...
人应该能从任何东西里
...and make something out of it.
得到些他想要的
For instance...
打个比方
...I look at you and I think:
看到你我就想
What could I use you for?
你可以为我做什么呢？
Get rid of this.
把这个处理掉
French.
法国佬
Put it downstairs. Here. Go ahead, thank you.
把这个放到楼下去，谢谢
Maybe we could work something out.
也许我们能干出点明堂来
- Good. - And send this to his wife.
- 很好 - 把这个交给他老婆
It was nice the way you asked the guy...
你问那家伙用哪只手打飞机那招够狠
I hope this don't shake Rita up.
希望这个不会吓到她
As I remember, she ain't that sentimental.
我记得她不是那么脆弱
That was quick. You think he's dead already?
够快的，他已经死了？
We have to do it by phone. I won't do it...
我们只能用电话联络
...if I have to wear a wire. No wires. Understand?
我身上不能带着窃听器，明白？
- You don't know what this is like. - Microprocessors.
- 你根本不知道这的情况 - 微处理器
- Micro what?
- 微什么？
We'll probably be at war with the Chinese in 20-odd years...
可能我们20年后就会和中国开战
...and Costello is selling them military technology.
现在卡斯特罗在向他们出售军事技术
Microprocessors, chips, computer parts.
微处理器，芯片，计算机部件
Anybody says anything about anything like that...
要是有人提到这方面的情况
...you let us know.
及时向我们报告
So who did the two guys from Providence?
普罗维登斯的案子是谁犯的？
Jimmy Pappas.
吉米・帕斯
What happened to Jimmy Pappas?
吉米・帕斯怎么了？
Jimmy had a rough month.
他这个月比较倒霉
Jimmy had a heart attack in jail...
他在监狱犯了心脏病
...and then he got himself knifed at Boston City Hospital.
然后在波士顿医院被人杀了
I believe it's been in the papers.
我想这些报纸上应该有报道
You seem quite happy with that result.
看来你对这个结果很满意
It's a fucking result.
只是他妈的结果
Yeah, but cui bono? Who benefits?
为什么呢？这事谁会受益？
Cui gives a shit? It's got a frigging bow on it.
管他呢，反正那案子是他犯的
I think you are a cop, my son.
你是块当警察的料，年轻人
- Where's your license? - What license?
- 你的执照在哪儿？ - 什么执照？
I don't see none. There's no such thing as a license, of course.
我没见过，根本没有执照这回事
But you, you definitely need to have fucking one.
看来你是真欠扁了
If you're not being run by us, you're being run by someone else.
就算我们不来扁你，也会有别人来
That means you're bringing undesirable elements...
也就是说你给卡斯特罗先生的地盘
...into Mr. Costello's area.
带来了他不喜欢的东西
I was going for my fucking cigarettes!
我他妈只是要拿烟
Hey.
嘿
That's Jimmy Bags.
嘿，他是吉米・派格斯
- He was rea... I don't know. - What the fuck you doing?
- 他要…我不知道 - 你到底干什么呢？
I'm in the hole, I pay him two grand.
我缺钱啊，我付给他两千
There's no profit, I pay him two grand.
我给他两千，赚不到什么钱
Then make more money. This is America.
那就多赚点钱，这可是美国
You don't make money, you're a douche bag. Now what you gonna do?
没钱你就等死吧 你想怎样？
- Make more money. - That's the spirit!
- 多赚钱 - 这就对了
- Oh, fuck. - Don't worry about it.
- 靠 - 别担心
The guy don't need any fucking teeth anyway.
那家伙根本就不需要牙
It's a small surveillance subunit, but it's mine.
这虽然只是个不起眼的监视小组 但我是头儿
I didn't take this job to fuck up or let anyone else fuck up.
我不想搞砸这个组 也不想别人搞砸
I handpicked this group. You're my A team. Now, our prim...
你们都是我亲自挑选的，都是我的人
Hi, Captain.
嗨，队长
This crazy fuck...
这疯小子…
...knocked Jimmy Bags' teeth out. - So?
…把吉米・派格斯的牙都打出来了 - 然后呢？
- He was... - He was reaching for his cigarettes.
- 他要… - 他要拿他的烟
You're gonna give me shit? It wasrt for no reason, Frank.
你想陷害我？ 弗兰克，我不是平白无故这么做
He reached into his coat.
那家伙把手伸到衣服里
I don't know if he's a bookie or what he's doing.
我不知道他是想掏赌注登记本还是什么
Well, you do know what a bookie does, don't you?
但你知道有赌注登记本的人是干什么的吧？
Yeah. Yeah, he pays you.
知道，交钱给你
Queenars compartmentalizing everything in SIU...
昆南把一切都划分到特别调查组
...which is the right thing.
这是对的
I don't trust half the troopers out there anymore.
就个人而言，我不信任外面的人
Bottom line...
关键是…
...we think we might have a problem.
我们可能出问题了
We think Costello's got a rat in the state police.
我们相信卡斯特罗安插了什么人在警队
- Really? - Yeah, really.
- 是吗？ - 是
Do we have direct access to Queenars undercovers?
我们能和昆南安插的卧底直接联系吗？
No, no, not presently.
不，目前还不行
But I'm working on that.
但我正在想办法
Here, Bill, this is for you.
比尔，这个给你
From now on, call the bar, ask for Mikey. Just Mikey.
从今以后打这个电话到酒吧 找麦克，只找麦克
You ask for Mikey because there is no Mikey.
你找麦克，是因为根本没麦克这个人
You wait. We'll call you.
然后你等着，我会给你打电话
- You got that? - Yeah, I got that.
- 明白吗？ - 明白
- Sorry, I didn't hear you. - I got that.
- 我没听见
Good.
很好
Hi, Dad.
嗨，爸爸
I got promoted. All right.
我升职了，好
Excuse me for one second.
失陪一下
You know...
你知道…
...if your father were alive...
如果你老爸还活着的话
...and saw you here sitting with me...
看到你跟我在一块
...let's say he'd have a word with me about this.
他会和我商谈这件事
In fact, he'd kill seven guys just to cut my throat.
实际上，即使需要连杀七人才能杀了我
And he could do it...
他也会做的
...which is maybe something you don't know about William Costigan Sr.
你对你老爸有些方面还不太了解
- So he never...? I mean, never? - No. No, no.
- 那他从来没… - 从来没有
He kept his own counsel. He never wanted money.
他有自己的原则 他对钱从来不感兴趣
You can't do anything with a man like that.
你不能跟这样的人合作
Your Uncle Jackie...
你叔叔杰西…
...he also would kill my entire fucking family if he saw me here with you.
如果看到我和你在一起的话 也会杀了我全家的
And I think about this.
我经常想起这些
So what the fuck are we talking about here?
我们他妈到底在谈什么？
Did you ever think about going back to school?
你有没有想过再回学校去？
School?
学校？
With all due respect, Mr. Costello...
恕我冒昧，卡斯特罗先生
...school is out.
我不会再回去了
Maybe someday you'll wake the fuck up.
也许有天你他妈能够清醒过来
Good day, Fathers.
你好，神父
- Mr. Costello. - Good morning, Francis, good morning.
- 卡斯特罗先生 - 早上好，弗兰克
You recall our chat?
你还记得我们以前谈的那些淫话？
Little boys...
小男孩…
...sucking on their peckers, et cetera and so forth...
吸自己的鸡鸡，进进出出
"I am as God made me." Was that your rationale?
“上帝创造了我”，这是你的准则吗？
May I remind you, in this archdiocese, God don't run the bingo.
我提醒你一下，在这个地盘上帝说了不算
May I remind you that pride comes before the fall.
我也提醒你，骄者必败
How's Sister Mary Theresa doing?
特丽莎修女最近怎么样？
We had a tasty relationship before she took her vows.
侍奉上帝之前，我和她的关系很滋润呢
Enjoy your clams, cocksuckers.
好好品尝你的鲜蛤吧，混蛋
Pay them.
给他们付账
Get the old bombardier a drink on the house.
给那老家伙来电喝的
- What do you got for me? - Uniform clipped him for suspended license.
- 问到了什么？ - 他因持用已吊销驾照被警察扣留
However, he's a subject of an open investigation...
他还是我们调查的对象
More than one. He's one of Costello's.
对不止一项罪案 他是卡斯特罗的手下
We're getting a warrant. Can't get an address off him.
我们正在申请搜查令 但是问不到他的地址
He paged his lawyer but the lawyer hasn't called back yet.
他已经传了他的律师 不过律师还没有回电
- Who's the lawyer? - Didrt know the name. Just a number.
- 谁是他的律师？ - 他也不知道名字，只有号码
Beeper number.
呼机号码
- And the guy didn't show up? - No.
- 律师还没来？ - 没来
- And he beeped him? - Twice.
- 呼他了？ - 两次了
Give me your phone. Turn that off.
把你电话给我，关掉那个
- What? - Turn the fucking camera off.
- 干吗？ - 把摄像机关了
Give it to me. He doesn't know what the fucking lawyer looks like.
他不知道他律师长什么样
Whose briefcase is this? All right.
这是谁的公文包？
- It's off? - You're good.
- 像吗？ - 不错
Afternoon, Mr. Fitzgibbons.
下午好，菲兹先生
- He can't do that. - He just did.
- 他不能这么干 - 他干了
- You my attorney? - What do you think?
- 你是我的律师？ - 你觉得呢？
Have you made statements or phone calls...
你有没有说过什么 打过什么电话，需要告诉我的？
I beeped you.
我呼了你
The card they gave me. That's it.
按他们给我的卡片，就这些
- That's it? - That's it.
- 就这些？ - 是的
You need to call your mother...
给你妈打个电话
...tell her you're not gonna be home for supper.
告诉她你今晚不能回家吃饭了
Camera's off. It's off. Call your mother.
摄像机关着，打吧
Lookit, they're suiting up for a raid right now.
警察正在整装准备突袭
I don't know where they're going, but they do. And so do you.
我不知道他们要去哪 但是他们知道，你也知道
So make the call.
快打电话吧
Lookit, fuckstick, you don't gotta trust me...
听着，猪头，你用不着相信我
...just listen to what I'm saying to you.
只要照我说的做
Mom, I'm not gonna make it home for supper.
妈，我不能回家吃晚饭了
Sorry, yeah, I got held up.
对不起，我有事耽搁了
Yeah, no, you carry on without me.
你先吃，不用等我了
I'll talk to you later. Okay.
回头再聊
Bye.
再见
Everybody out. Move.
大家快走，快
Thank you.
谢谢
So who are you?
你是谁？
I think you need a different attorney, Mr. Fitzgibbons. Have a great day.
看来你得另找一个律师了 费兹先生，好运
So when the fuck am I gonna get out?
我他妈什么时候能出去？
All right, run the last number he called. That's his house.
查查他最后打的电话，那就是他家
I'll swear to the judge I surveilled him there...
不管那是什么地址 我要监视那地方
...and abra-fucking-cadabra, we got a warrant.
我们有许可
- Why did you use my phone? - Because you didn't go in there.
- 为什么用我的电话？ - 因为你没进去啊
The light's nice here in the morning.
这儿早晨的光线真好
So do you wanna talk about last night?
想谈谈昨晚发生的事情吗？
You know, it's all right. Guys tend to make too big a deal out of it.
没什么，有的人可能太在乎这些了
It's actually quite common.
其实很平常
I gotta go to work.
我要去上班了
Do you lie?
你撒谎吗？
Why? Do you?
为什么？你撒谎吗？
No, I'm asking if you lie.
不，我问你撒谎吗
Honesty is not synonymous with truth.
“诚实”不是“真相”的同义词
Yeah, you lie.
哦，你也撒谎
You lie.
你也撒谎
Is it to do some good, to get somewhere personally...
这为了做好事，谋私利…
...or, what, just for the fuck of it?
还是纯粹是为了玩玩？
Well, I expect that some people do it to keep things on an even keel.
我认为有些人这么做使事态缓和
So you had a parent who was a drunk.
哦，那你父母都是酒鬼？
Did you?
你父母是吗？
No.
不是
Let's keep it with you.
还是谈谈你吧
Talk about how you feel.
说说你的感受
How I feel.
我的感受
- Fuck. - Brian, stop it.
- 妈的 - 布来恩，别这样
No. Please. No.
别，求你了
Ain't gonna hurt you.
不会伤害你的
You sit there...
当你坐在那儿…
...with a mass murderer.
面对一个杀人狂
A mass murderer.
杀人狂
Your heart rate is jacked.
你的心跳加快
And your hand...
你的手…
...steady.
毫不颤抖
That's one thing I figured out about myself in prison. My hand...
我在监狱里发现
...does not shake.
我的手不会颤抖
Ever.
永远不会
Wake the fuck up.
别他妈在这发呆了
There was a cop leaving when I came in.
我进来的时候有个警察从这出去
How did you know he was a cop?
你怎么知道他是警察？
Bad haircut, no dress sense and a slight, you know, air of scumbag entitlement.
头型差，不懂得如何穿衣 整个就一流氓样
- Do you see cops? - That's part of what I do.
- 你也辅导警察吗？ - 这也是我的工作的一部分
I normally don't see cadets who've been kicked out of the academy.
当然，从警校里被踢出来的比较少见
Oh, boy. You should get a better job, huh?
你应该找个更好的工作
Should I?
是吗？
So do they all come in here...
他们到这来…
...and cry, your cops?
大哭一场，都是你的警察？
Sometimes they do. Yeah, sure. Sometimes they cry, yeah.
有时候是的 没错，有时候他们会大哭一场
If they've had trouble at home, if they've had to use their weapons...
如果他们有什么家庭问题，或者开了枪
Use their weapons?
开枪？
Let me tell you something.
听我说
They signed up to use their weapons.
他们就是为了能开枪才加入警队的
Most of them, all right. But they watch enough TV...
大多数 但是他们看了太多的电视
...so they know they have to weep after they use their weapons.
所以以为开过枪后都要痛哭流涕
There is no one more full of shit than a cop.
再没有哪个比警察更假惺惺的了
Except for a cop on TV.
当然电视上的那些警察不算
I looked at your file.
我看了你的档案
I see that you have a record of assault.
你曾有过袭击他人的记录
Yeah.
是啊
So what was it like for you in jail?
在监狱是什么感觉？
What, you wanna hear about the showers? Is that what you wanna hear about?
你想听淋浴之类的事？ 那就是你想听的？
Did something happen to you?
在监狱里发生什么事了吗？
No.
没有
- Okay, let's do this. Come on, spread them. - Hey, you think you can pop somebody...
- 好吧，孩子，开始吧，伸开手 - 你以为你可以随便打人…
...and there's a special card to play? Jimmy Bags, whose jaw you broke...
自己很了不起吗？ 你把吉米・帕格斯的下巴都给打碎了
...happens to work undercover for the Boston Police Department.
他可是波士顿警察局的卧底
I'm going nuts. I can't be someone else every day.
我他妈的都要崩溃了 我不可能一天到晚伪装成别人
It's been a year. I've had enough!
都已经一年了，我受够了！
Calm down. Most people do it every day. What's the big deal?
冷静点，这世上大部分人每天都在伪装 有什么大不了的
- Well, I'm not them. I'm not them, okay? - Exactly.
- 我不是那种人，不是他妈的那种人 - 没错
You're nobody. You signed the papers, remember?
你是无名之辈 你签下了合同的，记得吗？
We're the only two people on this earth that even know you're a cop.
我们俩是这世上唯一知道你是警察的人
How about we just erase your file, huh?
我们把你的档案销毁怎么样？
How about we erase your file...
我们把你的档案销毁…
...and you're just another soldier for Costello...
那样你就只不过是 卡斯特罗的另一条走狗而已
...open to arrest for I don't know how many felonies. What do you say?
然后你就等着被捕吧 我都不知道你犯了多少罪
How about I fucking kill you, huh? How about I fucking kill you!
我要杀了你，我他妈的要杀了你！
- That was a joke. Come on. - That wasrt a joke.
- 他开玩笑的 - 我可没开玩笑
You play a tough guy, doesn't mean you are one...
你装得像个硬汉并不代表你就真是
...you lace-curtain, Irish fucking pussy! - Hey, hey! Stop it! Break it up! Stop it!
…你个爱尔兰脓包 - 放开，快放开！
- Fuck you, motherfucker! - Goddamn it, stop it! That's an order!
- 去你妈的！ - 给我松手，这是命令！
For chrissake, be smart.
天哪，理智点
If anybody's watching us now, how are we not supposed to arrest you?
要是被别人看见了，我怎么能不抓你呢？
Come on, get in the car.
现在上车
Both of you, get in the car.
你们俩都上车
When are you gonna take Costello?
你们什么时候抓抓卡斯特罗？
What's wrong with taking him on any one...
他干了这么多坏事，你我都清楚
...of the million felonies that you've seen him do or I've seen him do?
怎么不去抓他？
I mean, he murdered somebody, right?
他杀了人，对吧？
The guy fucking murders somebody and you don't fucking take him!
他杀了人你们都不来抓他
What are you waiting for? Do you want him to chop me up and feed me to the poor?
你还在等什么？ 你想看着我被碎尸后去喂穷人？
- That what you want? - That'd stick.
- 那就是你们想要的？ - 那可倒好了
Will you shut up?
你闭嘴
We are building a case and it takes time.
我们正在立案，这需要时间
You know that.
你知道的
Something's wrong.
有点不对劲
I'm telling you, something's wrong.
我告诉你，有点不对劲
Yeah, maybe.
是啊，可能是吧
Look, we need you to keep your ears open, all right?
听着，你要保持警惕，好吗？
No bullshit.
我是认真的
I think Costello's got a spy inside the Special Investigation Unit.
我们认为卡斯特罗 在特别调查组里安插了卧底
You serious?
真的？
I'm afraid so.
恐怕是的
Have you heard anything like that?
你有没有听说什么？
Jesus Christ.
哦，上帝啊
Hang tight for me, kid.
再坚持一阵，孩子
Just a little while longer.
再多坚持一阵
We are this close:
只差这么一点了
All right?
好吗？
What do you expect coming in here?
你来这想怎么样？
- I have to come here. - I know you have to come here.
- 我必须来 - 我知道你必须来
But now that you're here...
既然现在你已经来了…
...what do you want?
你想怎么样？
You want the truth?
你想听实话？
Valium.
安定药
If you lied, you would have an easier time getting what you wanted.
如果你撒谎，也许我就给你了
- What's that say about what you do? - We should have a few more meetings...
- 那是你的工作 - 在给你开处方之前…
...before we even talk about prescriptions. - Look, I'm having panic attacks.
…我还需要再和你好好聊聊 - 听着，我现在惊惶失措
Other night, I thought I was having a heart attack. I puked in a barrel on the way over.
有天晚上我还以为我犯了心脏病 我来这的路上还吐在垃圾箱里了
I haven't slept for fucking weeks.
我已经有好几周都没有睡觉了
- Is that true? - Yeah, that's true.
- 真的吗？ - 真的
I said something fucking true. I want some fucking pills...
我说了真话，我需要药片
...and you're gonna close my file?
你要干什么，想封了我的档案？
- I didn't say I'd close your file. No, l... - I thought I was supposed to tell...
- 我不会封你档案的，我… - 我以为在这里…
...the truth here, if only fucking here. - You are! Yes.
…我应该讲真话，只有在这 - 是的，你是的
A guy comes in here against every instinct of privacy, of self-reliance that he has...
人们来这里放弃了隐私和自尊
...and what do you do?
而你呢？
What do you do? You send him off on the street to score smack? Is that what you do?
你把他们扔到大街上去买毒品吸？ 这就是你的工作？
You're fucking ridiculous.
太荒谬了
Two pills?
2片？
Why don't you just give me a bottle of Scotch...
你为什么不直接给我一瓶威斯忌和一把枪
...and a handgun to blow my fucking head off?
让我轰掉脑袋算了？
- Are we done with this psychiatry bullshit? - You can leave!
- 这次的狗屁心理辅导结束了吗？ - 好了，你可以走了
What did I just put myself through? I'm out of here.
我受够了，我走了
And what if that was a legitimate threat? Think about it, fucking hotshot.
你这叫“合法威胁”，想想吧
Fuck.
靠
Why is the last patient of the day always the hardest one?
为什么每天最后一个病人都那么麻烦？
You're tired and you don't give a shit.
因为你累了，不想认真对待
- It's not supernatural. - Listen.
- 没什么不可思议的 - 听着
Listen. You know, I'm not just somebody that you have to see or they put you in jail.
听着，不要把我当成 为逃避坐牢而不得不见的人
Okay? I mean, if you're in distress, I will help you.
如果你觉得压力大，我会帮你的
What's this?
这是什么？
It's my card. And a prescription for 20 lorazepam.
我的名片，还有20粒安定的处方
Yeah?
是吗？
Is it enough to commit suicide?
这量足够自杀吗？
Maybe it is. All right? Okay?
也许，行了吧？
Have I done my job up to your goddamn standards?
根据你那该死的标准 我尽到我的职责了吗？
Because according to my standards, you fit the model of drug-seeking behavior.
以我的标准来说，你是典型的药品依赖
You know, and too damn bad if you don't like my initial clinical reaction.
太糟了，如果你不喜欢我最初的临床反应
Thank you.
谢谢
I'm transferring you to another counselor.
我会把你转给另一位心理医生的
- Good. - Okay.
- 很好 - 好吧
So you wanna get a cup of coffee?
想一起喝杯咖啡吗？
Bring it in here, please. Would somebody bring it in?
搬到这来，来个人把它搬到这来
Come on in.
进来
Our target is a major transaction of microprocessors.
本次行动的目标是微处理器交易
Yes, those.
是的
I don't know what they are, you don't know what they are. Who gives a fuck. Cash.
我不知他们是什么，你们也不知道 管他呢
Lots of cash is gonna change hands inside a building...
钱，大量的现金将在这栋楼里转手
...that we have under AV surveillance close-by.
我们已经做好视频监视
I know this location is not the best, but we had very little time to set up.
我知道摄像头位置不算好 但我们时间有限
- You guys know anything about this? - No.
- 你们知道这事吗？ - 不知道
Sullivars team will ID the bad guys and listen in on the phones.
苏利文警官的小组将负责 辨认他们的身份，监听电话
Our unit will not take action.
我们先不行动
I repeat, not take action, until a man that Captain Queenan has inside...
我再说一遍，我们先不行动 直到昆南警官的卧底…
...verifies the transaction. Are we clear?
…确认交易进行才行动，明白？
Anybody? Any questions? No? This is who we're after.
有什么问题吗？没？ 这就是我们要抓的
We've been after this cocksucker for a long time, and tonight...
我们已经盯了他很久了
...we are going to get him. Let's go to work.
今晚就能将他逮捕 开始工作吧
All right, you guys find out what we're doing and get on it.
你们去弄清楚我们到底要做什么
Sorry to get you last-minute, but things leak.
对不起，这么迟才通知你
This lead came from Queenars undercover guy.
这条消息是昆南手下的卧底提供的
I'm gonna smoke. You don't smoke? One of those fitness freaks, huh? Go fuck yourself.
我要去抽烟，你不抽烟对吗？ 怕得癌吗？去死吧
- Hi, Dad? - Yes.
- 嗨，爸爸 - 嗯
Yeah, something big came up at work.
工作上有点事情
- I'm not gonna be home for supper. - Too bad.
- 我晚上不能回来吃饭了 - 太糟了
Your mother worked all goddamn day.
你妈忙活了一天
We'll just have to sit down without you and your friends.
那我们就不等你和你朋友自己吃了
Oh, no, my friends are still coming.
不，我朋友还是要来的
So we'll just... I'll just see you for lunch instead tomorrow.
我们明天一起吃午饭吧
Your mother will be proud.
你妈妈会很高兴的
All right, thanks, Pop. Bye.
好的，谢谢，老爸
The readiness is all.
一切都准备好了
You know the players. Call the game.
你熟悉那群人，你负责吧
Thank you.
谢谢
- You ready? - Is your highness...
你准备好了吗
...gonna drop me off at confession before work, or fuck me, or what?
殿下是要工作之前带我去忏悔 和我上床还是什么？
What have you got to confess to that anointed pederast?
你要和那些狗屁神父忏悔什么？
A confessional seal, these days...
忏悔的保密，这年头…
...I'm not so sure.
我也不能保证
He'll operate the cameras. You ID the guys and log them.
很简单，他操作摄像头 你识别他们的身份
All cell-phone signals are under surveillance...
所有检测的手机信号都会在那上面显示
...through the courtesy of our federal friends over there.
多亏联邦调查局朋友的帮助
Patriot Act, Patriot Act. I love it, I love it, I love it.
爱国行动，爱国行动！ 我喜欢，我喜欢
Keep an eye on this one.
看着这个
All right, here we go.
好了，目标出现
There's Costello. Mr. French.
那个是卡斯特罗，法国佬
There's Fitzy, Delahunt...
菲兹和迪兰亨特
...and the new guy, Billy Costigan.
还有新人比尔・卡斯提根
Time is 10:46.
时间是10:46
All right, turn off your cell phones.
好了，把你们的手机都关掉
Fitzy's got the chicken. Check your weapons.
菲兹拿着货，大家检查一下武器
- We have a blind spot. - Why do we have a blind spot?
- 我们有个盲点 - 为什么？
We had two hours' notice. Two hours.
我们只有2小时的时间安装摄像头
- Fuck you think this is, NASA? - It never crossed my mind.
- 你以为我们是国家航空太空总署？ - 这我可没想过
- Have you got a camera in the back? - What back?
- 后面装了摄像头吗？ - 什么后面？
- How you going, Robert? - Good, Mr. Costello.
- 最近好吗，兄弟？ - 很好，卡斯特罗先生
I wanna tell you, at least two of these gents have machine guns.
我想告诉你他们至少两人带了机枪
He's from the Chinese government. He's scared shitless.
这位先生是中国政府官员 他现在吓坏了
Government man. Scared.
政府官员，害怕？
I'm concerned about a Chinaman who thinks it's wise...
我很担心你们这些中国人，居然自作聪明
...to come to a business transaction...
带着自动武器来做商业交易
For his own good, tell Bruce Lee and the Karate Kids...
为他自己好 告诉李小龙和他手下的空手道们
...none of us are carrying automatic weapons.
我们都没带自动武器
Because here, in this country...
因为在这个国家
...it don't add inches to your dick.
有枪不代表你牛x
You get a life sentence for it.
抓到就判重刑
If we had some Homeland Security money like some douche bags I could mention...
如果我们像国土安全部那些笨蛋有钱 我就能…
- Any calls? - They turned off their cell phones.
- 有电话吗？ - 他们把手机关了
Search randomly for calls made from the area.
随机搜索从那个区域打出的电话
Eight hundred and seven phones are live in this area.
有807个电话
Then narrow the area.
缩小区域
What you see there for service is what you're gonna get.
开着手机的就是你们要抓的
Why did they turn their phones off?
他们为什么把手机都给关了？
- Wait. There's still one phone up. - Where?
- 等等，还有一部手机开着 - 在哪？
The buyers are there.
买家在那
You know, direct contact with your guys would have its advantages.
和你卧底直接联系会更方便
Not to my guy.
不能和我的人联系
This is unbelievable. Who put the cameras in this place?
难以置信 到底是谁他妈的装的摄像头？
Oh, who the fuck are you?
你他妈是谁？
I'm the guy who does his job. You must be the other guy.
我是尽职干活的人 你一定是那个不尽职的了
If these Chinks wanna nuke Taiwan any time in this century...
如果这些中国佬 想在本世纪收复台湾的话
...they'd better shape up and show me 1 million dollars.
他们最好麻利点，给我那100万
What we generally do, in this country...
这是我们这个国家的规矩
...is one guy...
一手…
...brings the items...
交钱
...pays him.
交货
No "tickee"...
如果没钱
...no laundry.
就别做买卖
Go ahead, Fitz.
去，费兹
Cars are moving, but did you see anybody come out?
车子开了，看到有人出来了吗？
Please tell me those cars aren't empty.
告诉我这车不是空的
I mean, Jesus fucking Christ, please tell me that those Chinamers cars aren't empty!
快告诉我这车不是空的！
They didn't figure we had a navy.
他们不知道我们有海军
Did you put a camera in the back?
你在后面装摄像头了没有？
Can I talk to you for a second, please?
我能和你谈谈吗？
You stupid fucking hard-on!
蠢货！
You fucked this whole thing up!
你全搞砸了！
What the fuck did you do, you cocksucker? Let go of me!
你都干了什么？放开我！
I'm gonna rip your fucking arm off and shove it up your fucking ass!
我要揪下你的胳膊，塞进比屁眼！
Why don't we meet? Let me buy you an ice cream.
我们见个面吧，亲爱的 我给你买冰淇淋
I'm getting on a plane unless you put Queenan on.
我要走了，除非你叫昆南接电话
Queenan had a funeral to go to. This is my shift. Calm down.
昆南去参加葬礼了 现在我值班，你冷静一下
Why shouldn't I get on a fucking plane, huh?
为什么我他妈不能走，嗯？
Meet up? You actually want me dead?
见面？你真的想要我死吗？
Look, there is a rat in your unit. That is a fact, all right?
你的部门里有内鬼，这是事实
- Where's Queenan? - He's not here.
- 昆南在哪？ - 他不在
They knew you had cameras in the building. They knew everything.
他们知道你们在楼里装了摄像头 他们什么都知道
There is a leak from the inside. It's real. Man, smoke him out.
消息是内部的人泄漏的，这是千真万确 你得把他揪出来
Yeah, how do we do that, Mr. Genius-Who- Didrt-Even-Graduate-From-the-Academy?
怎么揪？ 你这连警校都没毕业的天才给我说说看
Disinform. Let it slip to SIU that you have a sealed wiretap warrant...
提供假情报 只你把情报透露给特别调查组的人
...for Costello's apartment. Don't tell anyone in our division, but tell SIU.
说你们在卡斯特罗的屋子里装了窃听器
Flush it down the pipe, see if it comes out on my end.
顺藤摸瓜 看看我能否抓住他
That's what we do first. Narrow it down.
这就是我们首先要做的 我们要缩小范围
- Where the fuck is Queenan, huh? - He's not here.
- 他妈的昆南在哪？ - 他不在
You wanna meet up or you got something real, call me back.
你要是想碰头，或是有新情况再打给我
- Changing your life radically.
从根本上改变你的生活
Change anything. Right? Change everything.
改变一切，对吗？
- Right? - Yeah.
- 对吗？ - 对
How long you been with this guy?
你和这人交往多久了？
- My boyfriend? - Yeah.
- 我男朋友？ - 是
- Four months. Almost four months. - Four months.
- 四个月，快四个月了 - 四个月
Do you love him?
你爱他吗？
It's a pretty serious relationship, yeah.
我们俩都很认真的
It's very serious.
很认真
Is he a headcase like me? I'm just curious.
他是不是也像我这样怪？我只是好奇
No more than I am.
不如我
I know that it's a serious relationship.
我知道这是一段认真的感情
I know there are ups and downs. Right?
感情总是会有起伏的
People have doubts and problems.
有疑惑，有问题
Well, not problems, but doubts.
也许称不上是问题，但是会有疑惑
What would you do if he was standing right there and he saw us?
如果他看到我们在一起，你会怎么办？
I would lie. Yeah, I would lie.
我会撒谎 是的，我会撒谎
You know, to keep things on an even keel, right?
为了保持事态平稳，对吧？
Right? We talked about that.
我们谈过这个的
- Morning. - Good morning.
- 早安
Want a French doughnut?
想吃法式甜圈吗？
Yeah.
好啊
- Hey, can I lookit? - Yeah.
- 我能看吗？ - 嗯
Sure.
当然
- All right, we're not having this out. - What?
- 我要把这个拿走 - 什么？
You don't see any pictures of where I came from.
你没见过我小时候的照片吧？
Look, I respect who you are...
我尊重你的现在
...just, you know, not in the living room.
只是这些不能放在客厅
We might have company.
可能会有客人来访
- Company? - Yeah, company.
- 来访？ - 是的，来访
- Hey, now, why do you work for the state? - Why not? You do.
- 你为什么为政府做事？ - 为什么不呢，你也是
No, what you do. The degrees and all, everything you got. You're hot shit.
你的工作埋没了你的才能，你这么辣
Yeah?
是吗？
So why do you make as much as a guidance counselor?
为什么要做心理辅导？
Because I believe in public service.
因为我相信公众服务
So now you're gonna fuck with me? So now you're gonna be ridiculous, huh?
你在耍我吗？ 很可笑吗？
- No, don't start with me. Don't... - Hey.
- 别跟我来这套，别... - 嘿
Ah, fuck with the fucking phone! Stop it!
讨厌的电话，能不能停下！
- The phone. - Forget the phone.
- 电话 - 别管电话
Get it. Answer it. Answer it.
不，不，接电话
This is your first phone call in the new house.
这是你新家的第一个电话
You live here now. You're a resident.
你住在这里,你是住户了
Mayor Sullivars office.
梅尔 苏利文办公室
Put Colin on the phone right now.
让科林接电话
Oh, my God. I'm sorry.
哦,天哪,对不起
What?
怎么了？
I think it's a guy with...
这个人好像...
- It's like a cancer guy. - Hello.
- 有喉癌 - 喂
What the fuck is it with you and your phone, huh?
你的电话是他妈怎么回事?
Something for work.
我…工作上的事
Hey. Nothing, nothing, nothing. It went dead. I don't know, I get...
没事没事，手机没电了 我事先不知道...
Was that that shrink cunt that answered the phone?
刚才是那个小妞接的电话？
Remember I told you that we were... She was gonna move in?
我说过她要... 搬进来和我住一起
- Yeah. - She moved in.
- 对 - 她搬进来了
- You better get organized, quick. - Hey, last time I checked, I tipped you off...
- 你最好把一切都搞定了 - 嘿,上次要不是我事先通知你
...and you're not in jail.
你早就进监狱了
- Are you listening to me? - Yeah.
- 你在听我说吗？ - 是的
Do you like Little Miss Thing sucking on your cock?
你想要那个女人吗?
Yes. Yes, I do.
当然
So earn it.
那就好好干
I'm getting the feeling...
我有种感觉...
...we got a cop in my crew.
...我的手下有警察的卧底
Yeah, I know, I'm kind of getting that feeling too.
我知道 我也感觉到了
He's one of yours. Inside.
是你们的人
Have you seen anything?
有什么发现吗？
I got no access to Queenars undercover files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
我无权查看昆南的卧底档案 只有他和迪克曼两个人知道卧底的情况
- Doing my best. - Your best?
- 我正在尽力 - 尽力?
What do you think we're in, the fucking haberdashery business?
你以为我们是做服装买卖的？
Look, Frank, if you don't relax...
听着，弗兰克，如果你不放轻松...
If you don't relax, I can't relax. All right? Now, what I need you to do...
听着，弗兰克，如果你不放轻松 我就不能放松,我现在需要的是
...get me information on the people with you last night. Your crew.
昨晚和你一起的那些手下的信息
Get me social-security numbers, get me...
给我他们的社会保险号码...
Get you? Give you? Who the fuck do you work for?
给你？给你？ 你他妈到底给谁干活?
All right, all right. Frank, Frank, Frank. All right. I'm sorry.
好了…弗兰克… 好了，对不起
If you could, please. What I need are SS numbers, DOBs...
请您帮我搞到 他们的社会安全号，出生日期
...just all the pedigree information so I can run it on my end and we can ID the prick.
所有能证明那些人来历的资料
If you can get me that information...
你给我搞来那些信息
...I can... We're gonna handle it. I can handle it.
我就能搞定的
Calm down, or you'll shoot in your pants.
冷静，不然你要尿裤子了
I'll get you the records and whatnot.
我会给你你要的资料
But listen to me, son. Don't disappoint me on this...
但是听我说，孩子 不要让我失望...
...or some other guy will be putting their fat cock...
不然的话...
...up Little Miss Freud's ass.
就会有别人来搞你女朋友了
How are you, Francis?
你还好吗，弗朗西斯？
- My mother called me Francis. - I know she did.
- 我妈叫我弗朗西斯 - 我知道
And your father called you the tumor.
我还知道你爸叫你肿瘤
And what did your father call you, Charlie?
那你爸怎么叫你，查理？
Oh, yeah, I forgot. He wasrt around.
哦，我忘了,你根本就没老爸
You have a boss that has a laryngectomy?
你老板做过喉头切除手术?
No, no, no. That was a guy who works for me.
不，那只是我的一个手下
You're lying to me.
你骗我
Not exactly.
不尽然
What did you do with the real microprocessors, Frank?
你把那些真的微处理器怎么样了，弗兰克？
Microprocessors.
微处理器
Oh, yeah.
噢，对了，我听说了
I heard the story. You arrested some Chinese government guys...
你在边境抓到了什么中国政府官员
...at the border carrying some light sockets or something.
那人身上带着几块电灯插座
I can't wait to wipe that fucking smirk off of your face.
我真想把你那张假笑的脸给撕下来
Wouldrt you rather wipe my ass for me?
你这混蛋就配给我擦屁股
There are certain parts of my job that I'm not gonna be able to talk to you about.
我工作中一些事情不能告诉你
And I cannot allow you to jeopardize an ongoing investigation...
我也不容许有任何东西威胁到我们的调查
...or your life.
还有你的生命
No, really, there are things you don't even wanna know about.
真的，有些事你不会想知道
Okay, then just say that.
好，你说清楚就好
All right, I will.
好的，我会的
Oh, that's the movers.
搬家的人来了
Yeah, you still wanna stay?
这么说你还想住在这？
- Yes. - Yeah?
- 是的 - 是吗?
Come on, I'm coming! It's the worst timing.
来了! 来的真不是时候
I'm gonna get you.
我会抓到你的
If you could've, you would've.
你要是抓得到我早抓了
But I guess you like to go at your own pace.
不过我猜你大概喜欢慢慢来
Excuse me. Got a date with some angels.
失陪了，我和天使有约
Frankie.
弗兰克
Your mother forgives me.
你妈妈已经原谅我了
You take off an armored car at the mall.
你带着钱下车干什么去了？
What the fuck, you pay guineas in Providence?
是去给那些普罗维登斯 意大利佬送钱去了吗？
- Fucking now I do! - What the fuck do you do?
- 我没有! - 那你干什么去了？
I gotta pay Costello for him to trade me to the FBI? Because that's what he does.
我得在卡斯特罗把我 卖给联邦调查局前把钱给他 他总是这么干的
FBI? What the fuck you talking about, FBI?
联邦调查局？你他妈的在说什么？
My God, is that French out there?
天啊，弗兰克在外面吗？
What the fuck did you just say about the FBI?
你说的联邦调查局到底怎么回事？
Forget what I said. I'm fucking high.
没什么，我吸毒兴奋瞎说的
Whatever may be going on in that very fucking poor...
不管你那弱智的脑袋是怎么想的...
...very limited brain of yours, I am not gonna hurt you, all right?
我是不会伤害你的
- Just tell me what you fucking said. - Forget it.
- 再说一遍你刚说的话 - 没什么
I'm high. I'm fucking high. I must be high. I'd never say what you thought I said.
我吸毒兴奋了,我兴奋的飘起来了 刚才那些话都是瞎说的
Fuck!
去死!
Now, what the fuck did you just fucking say?
你刚才他妈到底说什么了！
Why do you think he never gets busted? Costello's a protected FBI informant.
为什么他从没被抓过？ 卡斯特罗是受联邦调查局保护的线人
He'll trade you out.
他会把你们都出卖的
I thought I was supposed to go into shock.
我还以为中了枪我会休克过去
I'm not in shock. It fucking hurts!
没有，我现在好痛！
It fucking hurts!
疼死了!
Hey. It's me.
嗨，是我
- What are you doing here? - Come here.
- 你来这干什么？ - 过来
Costello's giving people up to the FBI.
卡斯特罗把人卖给联邦调查局
- The FBI? - He is giving information to the FBI.
- 联邦调查局? - 他给联邦调查局工作
He's a protected fucking informant.
他是他妈的被保护的线人
I mean, aren't they always trying to make it a federal case and it never gets made?
他们不是总想弄成个联邦案件 却总没成功？
Go around the back. I'll open the door. Go on.
到后面去，我来开门，快去
- Here's some ice water. - Oh, thanks. Thanks.
- 这是冰水 - 谢谢
That's my son, Patrick.
那是我儿子，帕特里克
- Goes to Notre Dame. - Oh, yeah?
- 他在圣母大学读书 - 是吗?
My wife's asleep but she left some supper out. You want something to eat?
我太太睡觉了，她给我留了晚饭 你要吃点吗？
No. No, thanks.
不，谢了
Yeah, come on, man. You have some supper. We'll talk in the kitchen.
吃点晚饭，我们到厨房里谈
Come on.
来吧
You want some coke?
想来点儿白粉吗？
There it is.
给你
Don't move till you're numb.
在你麻木之前不要动啊
Come on. Get inside.
进来
Boss wants your real name...
老板要你的真实姓名...
...your social and license number, your bank account numbers.
你的社会保险号，银行帐号
I don't have a bank account.
我没银行帐号
- I'm a cash business myself. - What's he doing, setting up IRAs?
- 我也喜欢现金交易 - 他要干什么，给我们开养老帐号？
Just fill the fucking paper in. Your real name and all your account numbers.
少废话，把表填了 你的真名和帐号
Then we wait here.
然后我们在这里等着
- You're shitting me. - No, I ain't.
- 开玩笑吧 - 没有
Put the forms in there.
把表放进去
I don't know if this is how you spell "citizens."
我不知道怎么拼“市民”
But fuck it, you know?
管他呢,你知道吗?
No, no, no. Come here.
不对，我来吧
What, are you fucking retarded or something?
你他妈是不是弱智啊？
That ain't fucking right.
肯定不是那么写
Are you kidding me?
开玩笑吧?
Look at this. Look.
看这个,看
"Citizens." Look.
市民
Billy, he said to stay here.
比尔，他说让我们呆在这儿
Yeah. I'm not sitting here without a tetanus shot.
我他妈还要回去吸毒呢
Where the fuck are you going?
你他妈去哪儿？
I'm not staying, all right? You can tell him I said that.
我不想呆在这，好吗？ 告诉他我说的
- Hey. - Hi.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- It's pouring out there. - Yeah.
- 外面雨很大 - 是啊
Look...
听着...
...if this is inappropriate, l... - No.
- 如果你觉得不合适,我... - 不
No, it's not inappropriate. You're not a patient.
不，没什么不合适的 你又不是我病人
So you moving out or you moving in?
你是搬出还是搬进？
I've still got three weeks left on the lease.
租约还剩三周
That's me.
那是我
Yeah, I know.
我知道
- Hedging your bets? - No. No.
- 你是不是举棋不定了？ - 没有
You have to choose.
你得选择
- You have to make a... - A decision.
- 你得做出... - 决定
A decision. And, you know, you have to stick by what you choose.
决定，然后就要坚持你的选择
- You have to... - Move in with your boyfriend?
- 你要... - 搬到男朋友那里?
Yes. Otherwise it's...
否则的话...
Oh, I know, I know. I know.
我知道,我知道,我知道
I have to say your vulnerability is really freaking me out right now.
我得说，你这种受伤的样子 现在有点让我害怕
Is it real?
是真的吗？
I think so.
我想是吧
You don't have any cats.
你没养猫
No.
恩
I like that.
我喜欢这样
I don't get it.
我不明白
We are all convinced that Costello has at least...
我们都相信卡斯特罗...
...one mole inside the Special Investigations Unit.
在特别调查组里至少安插了一个内鬼
You will investigate everybody and anybody.
你要调查所有的人
Well, that's not exactly a dream job for a cop.
这可不是什么好差事啊
We looked at all possible candidates. You have an immaculate record.
在所有的候选人里 你的档案完美无缺
Some people don't trust a guy with an immaculate record. I do.
有些人不信任这种完美的人 但是我信任
I have an immaculate record.
我也是完美的人
How is your wedding coming along?
婚礼的事准备的怎么样了？
Great. Great. She's a doctor.
不错，她是医生
- That's outstanding. - Yeah.
- 厉害 - 是
Marriage is an important part of getting ahead.
婚姻是人生重要的一环
Lets people know you're not a homo. Married guy is more stable.
至少人们会知道你不是同性恋 而且你本人看上去也更可靠些
People see the ring, think at least someone can stand him.
人们看到你的戒指就会想 至少还有个人能忍受这个混球
Ladies see the ring, they know you must have some cash and your cock must work.
女人看到你的戒指,立刻就知道你至少有点儿钱 而且你的老二还好用
Yeah, it's working. Overtime.
是好用,还能加班呢
- I'm glad to hear that. - Thank you.
- 很高兴听到这个 - 谢谢
Be dirty, be dirty.
来啊,来啊
Yeah...
哦...
Frank. The fuck is wrong with you?
妈的，你有毛病啊?
- See anything you like, Col? - I almost fucking shot you.
- 你不喜欢吗？ - 我差点就开枪了
- You're not indulging in self-abuse, are you? - Sit down.
- 你不喜欢自虐吧？ - 坐下
I hope you're not turning into one of them sob sisters wants to get caught.
我希望你不会背叛我
You're not cracking up, are you?
你还承受的住吗？
- I don't crack up. - Pick a place like this...
- 我不会崩溃的 - 选这么个地方见面...
...where any cop could see you. Jesus.
太容易被警察发现了
If this is such a fucking bad idea why'd you show up?
如果这主意很糟，为什么你还来?
I own the place.
因为这里是我的地盘
Why am I not fucking surprised?
什么？我他妈的太吃惊了
- All right, lookit, I gotta tell you... - You're getting reassigned. I know.
- 我有些事要告诉你... - 你被分配了其他任务
How the fuck do you know that?
你他妈怎么知道的？
- Where'd they put you? - Hey, Frank.
- 他们让你干什么？ - 弗兰克
I gotta find myself.
我要查出"我自己"
You're telling me, sonny boy.
快告诉我，小子
I gotta find the guy you got in the department.
我得找出你在警局里安插的内鬼
With everybody looking up their own ass and you looking for yourself...
大家都自顾不暇 再加上你自己就是那个内鬼...
...I put my money on nobody finds nothing.
我打赌到头来他们还是什么也查不到
I know, but, Frank, lookit. For me, you gotta lay low.
我知道，但是弗兰克，为了我 你现在要低调行事
- Right now. - Collie...
- 就现在 - 科林...
...laying low is not what I do.
低调行事不是我的风格
All right, fucking Big Daddy Frank. Fucking perfect.
没错，你厉害，什么都不怕
What good am I to you if you don't listen to me?
如果你不听我的劝告，那要我干什么？
Queenan is compartmentalizing. He's splitting everything up.
昆南现在把他的部门和我们的分开
He's fucking smart. You know this.
他很聪明，这点你清楚
I can get the rat. You just gotta let me do it my way, Frank.
弗兰克，我能找到内鬼 但是你要让我放手干
Okay.
好吧
But Colin, I hope I won't have to remind you...
不过科林,我不想再提醒你...
...that if you don't find that cheese-eating rat bastard in your department...
如果你还找不到内鬼的话
...most likely, it won't be me who suffers for it.
到头来最先倒霉的可不是我
Now, why would you have to remind me of that?
何必一再提醒我这点呢？
Would I be any good at what I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
难道这对我现在的工作有任何帮助吗？
Frank, you gotta trust me.
弗兰克，你得相信我
All right? Just trust me, Frank.
好吗？相信我，弗兰克
Hey, it fucking involves lying and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
要是需要撒谎的话 你知道我他妈很在行的
Right?
好吗？
Maybe because it's always been so easy...
也许是因为我玩女人太容易了
...for me to get cunt that I never understood jerking off in a theater.
我就不明白为什么 有人要在电影院里玩手淫
Christ.
妈的
Who knows what's easy?
谁知道究竟什么事情容易呢？
Colin, I know you'll take care of business.
科林，我相信你能办好这件事
Shit!
妈的！
Fuck.
干！
Hey, how you doing?
嗨，你好吗？
Hi, Darlene, hi.
嗨，亲爱的
- That's it for me. - Yeah, see you.
- 我走了 - 再见
Have a good one.
祝你愉快
I smell a rat.
我闻到了内鬼味
Jesus Christ.
妈的
You got a girlfriend?
你有女朋友吗？
No.
没有
No, no. Why, what does that matter?
为什么问我这个，有什么问题吗？
It depends.
那要看情况了
I'm sure by now you know...
我相信你已经知道...
...I got an informer in my outfit.
我的手下里有卧底
Cop.
条子...
Staties, Boston Police Department, I'm not sure.
或者是州警 我也不太清楚
Jesus Christ.
妈的
Are you sure it's not the FBI?
你肯定不是联邦调查局？
It ain't the FBI.
不是联邦调查局
Ex-wife.
前妻
Old girlfriend.
女友
Or stupid.
还有愚蠢
That is what brings you down in this business.
干我们这行的最怕这几样
Stupid, huh?
愚蠢？
Well, I guess that leaves me out.
至少我不在此列
You know, past days, situation like this, I kill everybody.
要是这种事发生在以前 我早就把所有人都宰了
Everybody who works for me.
所有我的手下
Right. You know, Frank...
弗兰克，我们的人...
...I look around at your other guys...
那些人...
I mean, they're all murderers, right? Right?
他们都杀人不眨眼，对吧？
And I think, "Could I do murder?"
我想，我能不能也像他们一样？
And all I can answer myself is:
我所知道的只是
"What's the difference?"
我和他们又有什么分别呢？
Give them up to the Almighty.
留给上帝发落吧
You see, that's my point, you know?
我想说的就是
You accuse me once, I put up with it.
指责我一次，我还能容忍
You accuse me twice...
指责我两次...
...I quit.
我退出不干了
You pressure me to fear for my life and I will put a fucking bullet in your head...
你要是想让我胆战心惊...
...as if you were anybody else. Okay?
我二话不说就崩了你的头，懂吗？
You got something you wanna ask me?
你有事要问我吗？
Look, you're 70 years old, Frank. I'm just saying, okay?
你都70岁了，弗兰克 我只是说
One of your guys is gonna pop you.
总有人会出卖你的
- One of your guys is gonna pop you. - Yeah, yeah.
- 会有人的 - 我知道
As for running drugs, what the fuck are you doing?
指控你搞毒品勾当 你到底在搞什么？
You don't need the money or the pain in the ass. And they will catch you.
你根本就不缺钱花 但你就像他们的眼中钉肉中刺
I haven't needed the money...
自从我三年级的抢了同学的牛奶钱后
...since I took Archie's milk money in the third grade.
我就不缺钱花了
Tell you the truth, I don't need pussy anymore, either.
说实话，我也不需要女人
But I like it.
但是我喜欢
Point I'm making here is, Bill...
我想说的是，比尔...
...I got this rat...
现在我这有内鬼...
...this gnawing, cheese-eating, fucking rat...
恶心，该死的内鬼
...and it brings up questions.
这使我产生了置疑
You know. See, Bill, like, you're the new guy.
比尔你是新来的
Girlfriend...
还记得我们刚才说的前妻女友什么的吗
Why don't you stay in the bar that night I got your numbers?
让你写号码那天，为什么你不呆在酒吧里？
Social-security numbers.
社会安全号
- Yeah. - Everybody's fucking numbers.
- 是的 - 所有人的号码
Is there something that you just wanna go ahead and ask me?
这就是你想要问的?
Because I'll give you the fucking answer, all right?
我他妈现在就回答你
Frank, look at me. Look at me.
看着我，弗兰克
I'm not the fucking rat. Okay?
我他妈的不是内鬼，懂吗？
I'm not the fucking rat.
我不是那个内鬼！
Start with you agree there is a rat.
这么说你也认为有内鬼了？
You said there is one, all right?
是你说的有内鬼
I base most of what I do on the idea that you're pretty good at what you do.
我这么说是因为 我知道你对这种事情很在行
Sure. Sure, Will.
很好,很好
You, William. What would you do?
你，威廉，你会怎么做？
Frank, how many of these guys...
弗兰克，这里有多少人...
...have been with you long enough to be disgruntled?
有资格坐上你的位置？
Think about it. You don't pay much, you know.
你仔细想想 你给的钱不多
It's almost a fucking feudal enterprise.
你给的钱只够买棺材的
The question is, and this is the only question...
问题是，这是唯一的问题...
...who thinks that they can do what you do better than you?
谁觉得他比你有能耐，可以取代你？
The only one who could do what I do is me.
唯一能取代我的人就是我
Lot of people had to die for me to be me.
其他能取代我的都死了
You wanna be me?
你想取代我吗？
I probably could be you. Yeah.
我也许可以
Yeah, I know that much.
这我知道
But I don't wanna be you, Frank.
但我不想取代你，弗兰克
I don't wanna be you.
我不想
"Heavy lies the crown" sort of thing.
王冠难戴啊
Yeah.
没错
- Francis. - I'm out of here. You'll set the alarm...
- 弗朗西斯 - 我要走了，别忘了把警报...
- Yeah, all right. I'll see you at Christmas. - All right. Good night.
- 好的,圣诞节见 - 好吧,晚安
You know what I like about restaurants?
为什么大家喜欢餐厅？
The fucking food? I don't know. What?
因为有吃的？我不知道
You learn a lot watching things eat.
看别人吃饭你能学到很多东西
There's a boat coming up Gloucester.
有艘船货要到格拉斯特
French will give you all the details. Don't forget.
具体情况法国佬会告诉你
Eat something, for Christ's sake.
吃点东西吧，看在上帝份上
In the future, I tell you to do a thing, you fucking do it. You got that?
以后叫你做什么你就做什么，明白了吗？
I got it. Okay?
明白了,好的
Excuse me...
对不起...
...French, I forgot my... - Okay, Francis.
- 不好意思，法国佬，我的... - 好的，弗朗西斯
...cigarette.
香烟
Eat something.
吃点东西吧
Problem?
有什么问题吗?
Yeah, I got a problem. I run rat fucks like you, okay? I don't like them.
是，我确实有点问题 我才是主管，你少来这掺合
The day you wouldn't take a promotion, let me know.
哪天你不想升官了，记得告诉我一声
If you'd taken care of this I wouldn't be here.
如果你能处理好的话 根本就不会叫我来
- Fuck yourself, you piece of shit. - I need the identity of your undercovers.
- 你去死吧，臭狗屎 - 我要你那个卧底的身份
Blow me. Not literally. Unfortunately, there's no promotion involved for you.
去死吧 你还没到那个级别
Fucking prick.
混蛋
- Hi, captain. - Look who's here. The prom queen.
- 嗨，队长 - 瞧瞧，这不是明星来了吗
- They are not happy with me. - What do you expect?
- 大家好像都不喜欢我 - 你想怎么样呢？
Everybody knows you've been assigned here to find Costello's rat.
大家都知道你被分配到这里 查卡斯特罗的卧底
They want to find the leak as much as you do.
他们和你一样想揪出那个家伙
Like I said, two days ago, my guy damn near found out who Costello's rat is.
两天前,我的卧底差点就查出 卡斯特罗卧底的身份
- But he lost him in the streets. - Really?
- 不过最后在街上跟丢了 - 真的？
- Well, did he get a look at the guy? - No.
- 他看到那人的相貌了没？ - 没有
I mean, nothing? Like, I mean, anything that could help us.
什么都没有？ 任何信息可能都对我们有帮助
No.
没有
So you got any advice for me? Just, I mean, generally.
有什么建议给我吗？
Costello can't do much business without coordinating with his source...
没有特别调查组内鬼的信息
...who is here in SIU.
卡斯特罗没法做太多的生意
Follow Costello. You'll find his rat.
跟踪卡斯特罗就会找到他的线人的
You're gonna be looking at my people...
你要去查我的人...
...going through their bank statements, their phone calls and medical records.
查他们的银行账户，电话记录和医疗记录
Don't be surprised if they don't buy you a beer or invite you into their homes.
他们不会请你去喝酒或去家里作客
Let me get you a coffee.
要来杯咖啡吗
If I wasrt with the Massachusetts State Police...
如果我没有当州警...
...if I did it full-time, law school...
而是选择去法学院学习的话...
...I'd be through it in a year.
我一年就可以完成学业
If I wasrt a trooper.
如果我不在警队
But another city. I was thinking that.
在另一个城市也许情况会好很多
Another city.
另一个城市
Another city, huh?
另一个城市?
Yeah, well, that would be a clean slate.
那就可以重新开始了
I want you to know, you don't got to stay.
我希望你知道，你没有必要留下来
If we're not gonna make it...
如果我们最后没有走到一起...
...it's gotta be you that gets out, because I'm not capable.
你一定要先离开我，因为我做不到
I'm fucking Irish. I'll deal with something being wrong for the rest of my life.
我他妈的是爱尔兰人 我只会一辈子生活在错误的阴影中
It might not be a bad idea, you know, another city.
也许我们真应该到另一个城市去
- Of course I know how to spot a cop. - How's that?
- 我当然知道怎么识别警察 - 怎么识别？
If he's not paying attention to us, he's a cop.
他对我们视而不见，他就是警察
Lookit. You see that guy over there? Right over there.
看到那边那个人了吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Not paying attention to us. He's a cop.
他根本没在意我们，他是警察
- Okay. - You get it now, do you?
- 对 - 你明白了吧
- What about this guy? - Cop.
- 这个呢？ - 警察
Hey, how you doing? What kind of dog is that?
你好，这是什么狗？
She ignored us so she must be a cop.
她没理我们，她也一定是警察
She's probably the fucking police commissioner.
她是她妈的警察局长
You can get out of here. I'm using a new crew tonight. New guys.
你可以走了，今晚我们用新人
- I thought I was on for this. - I changed my mind. Take the night off.
- 我以为这票有我呢 - 我改主意了，今晚你休息
- Jimmy, bring a mop. - Out the back.
- 吉米,拿个拖把来 - 从后门走
There's guys who answer the questions right...
有人总能很好的回答问题...
...and there's guys that don't. - And a pail.
还有些人不能
You're a cop.
你是警察
What?
什么？
You ignored us, you're a cop.
你无视我们，所以你是警察
We're guessing who cops are. You know, most good-Iooking women are cops.
我们在猜谁是警察 你知道好看的女人一般都是警察
Well, I'm going home, all right? He's playing with his new guys.
我要回家，你们和新人玩吧
- See you later, all right? - See you later.
- 回见
He's moving something with all new guys. A whole new crew.
他这次要带新人去行动
No, no, I can't tell you what or where. It's probably disinformation.
我不能告诉你时间地点 这些有可能是假情报
Just keep following him, all right? Listen, I need to see you today.
你继续跟踪他就是了 我今天要见你
- Tomorrow. - No, no, no. Today.
- 明天 - 不，今天
- You heard nothing about drugs? - No.
- 你没听人提起毒品？ - 没有
Nothing about new guys? Nothing about Gloucester?
也没听说新人，格拉斯特什么的？
Not a thing. And I would have. That information would have come to me.
什么都没有,如果有什么消息的话 我肯定会知道的
It ain't Bill.
不是比尔
No way, he says.
他没说出去
Follow Costello. You'll find his rat.
跟踪卡斯特罗就会找到他的内鬼
Yeah, this is Sergeant Sullivan.
我是苏利文警官
I want constant surveillance on Captain Queenan, starting right now.
我要对昆南队长进行连续监视 现在就开始
Good. Thank you.
好，谢谢
Can I ask a question, sarge? Why the fuck are we following Captain Queenan?
警官，能不能问你个问题？ 我们他妈的为什么要跟着昆南队长？
To find out about the good Catholic life?
看看好天主徒是怎么生活的？
I have to follow every lead, however unlikely...
我必须追查每条线索 不管有多不可思议
...however fucking painful it might be to your delicate fucking sensibilities.
不管你脆弱的感性有多么难以接受...
Who told you I had delicate sensibilities?
谁说我脆弱？
- I just don't like it, sarge. Don't feel right. - I have reason to believe...
- 我只是不喜欢这样,这样不对 - 我有理由相信
...that Captain Queenan is Costello's rat.
昆南队长就是卡斯特罗的内鬼
So just follow him and don't get made.
跟踪他，注意不要被他发现
Sarge, we got the target coming out.
警官，目标出来了
Hey. Where are you?
嘿，你在哪？
Look down the car.
回头
- You got me? - Yeah, I gotcha.
- 看到我了吗？ - 看到了
Is there a reason you would have a tail?
有人跟踪你吗？
No.
不会
- Because I think... - Billy, I don't have a tail.
- 但是我觉得… - 比利,没人跟踪我
Get off at the next stop, all right? South Station. You wait there 10 minutes.
下一站下车，南站 在那里等10分钟
South Station. Wait 10 minutes.
南站，等10分钟
He just went into a building down the waterfront. 344 Wash.
他进了一栋楼，沃时街344号
You got that? 344 Wash.
听到了吗？沃时街344号
Yeah, he went up to the top floor.
他去了顶楼
Building's empty. No tenants here.
顶楼空着，没人住
He's got dope coming in. I don't know where. He...
有批毒品运进来了 但我不知道详情
He's getting spooky, captain.
他现在很神经质
- What? - I just saw him.
- 什么意思？ - 他失去理智了
He had blood on his hands. He's lost his fucking mind.
我看到他满手是血
I don't know what we're doing here, boys.
不知道我们来这干什么
He's not including his regular guys. But I'll tell you something.
他不用他的老手下了
Sooner or later he's gonna find out who I am and he's gonna fucking kill me.
告诉你，迟早他会知道我的身份的 他会干掉我的
- I know it. He's gonna fucking kill me! - All right!
- 我知道，他会干掉我 - 好了
I think we got him. I think Queenars meeting with him right now.
找到他了，昆南正在和他接头
All right, all right. Listen to me.
好了，听我说
I'm really sorry for your trouble. I swear to God I am.
很抱歉，我会把你弄出来
I'll get you out of this. I can't do it overnight but I'll get you out.
也许需要些时间，但我一定会把你弄出来
Yeah?
是吗?
Hey, get the van. We're moving. Heavy work.
上车，有行动 大动作
- What about the FBI? - They're compromised.
- 联邦调查局怎么办？ - 他们那边泄漏消息
- They're what? - They're fucked.
- 他们什么？ - 他们完蛋了！
- Yeah. - Where are you?
- 喂 - 比利，你在哪？
We've been trying to reach you. We found the rat.
我们到处找你 找到内鬼了
Listen, we're gonna take him out. Lookit:
现在我们要赶去干掉他
The address is 314 Washington Street. You got it?
地址是沃时街314号，听见了吗？
All right, we'll see you there.
到那里见
- What? - You were followed.
- 什么？ - 你被跟踪了
- By who? - By Costello's people.
- 被谁？ - 卡斯特罗的手下
- Impossible. - One of the cops...
- 不可能 - 有可能，他在警局里有线人...
...he's got on the inside tipped him. Come on. Come on.
快走,快走
Come on!
快走!
What the fuck is going on?
这他妈怎么回事？
Fucking shit. Looks like Queenars meeting with all of them.
看来都是来跟昆南接头的
Yeah, he must be our guy.
对，昆南就是内鬼
Sarge, we gotta get him out of here. Those guys aren't fucking around.
我们得要救他出来 那些人可不是开玩笑的
Ah, Christ, it's too late. Let's go back up.
太迟了，快回去
- Shit! - You got to get out of here!
- 妈的! - 你快走!
- Take the fire escape. - What about you?
- 走消防梯 - 你怎么办？
I'll be fine. But if you get made I can't protect you. Now, go!
我没事的,要是你被抓到了 我就保护不了你了，快走!
- One of you mugs got a light? - Where's your boy?
- 能借个火吗？ - 人呢?
- He's studying law at Notre Dame. - Where's your fucking boy?
- 在圣母大学读法律 - 你的卧底在哪？
- Hey! Hey! - Goddamn motherfucker!
- 嘿,嘿! - 妈的!
- Fucking kill you! - Where's your fucking boy?
- 我杀了你! - 他妈的，你的卧底在哪？
What the fuck was that? Did you fucking see that?
那他妈是什么东西? 你看到了吗?
Sarge, something just came off the building.
警官，有东西从楼顶掉下来
What the fuck?
妈的
What do you mean, off the building?
什么叫从楼顶掉下来？
- Something came off the fucking roof. - It's a fucking body.
- 有东西从楼顶掉下来 - 是尸体，那是尸体
We can't get a visual. Want us to get out?
我们的视线被阻 你想叫我们下车去确定一下吗？
We gotta get on foot if you want me to get up on this thing.
我们的下车才看得见
- Where were you? - What happened?
- 你他妈去哪了？ - 出什么事了？
You're fucking late! Get in the van!
你他妈迟到了，快上车!
What do you mean, off the roof?
你说有东西坠楼是什么意思？
What's going on? I came to meet you.
这他妈怎么回事？我赶来找你们
- What the fuck...? - Get in the van!
- 妈的... - 快上车!
I got four armed men right out front. You want us to pursue?
警官，有4名带枪男子出来 要不要我们行动？
No, do not pursue. Stay in the car.
不要行动，呆在车里
- Fuck. No fucking pursuit. - I need information.
- 靠! 不准行动！ - 我需要知道
What came off the roof?
什么东西从楼顶掉下来?
- No pursuit. - That's bullshit.
- 不追 - 真的他妈的扯淡
Fuck this.
去他的
Fitzy! Get in the van!
快进车里来!
Get in the fucking van! Let's go! Move!
上车!走，快走!
All right. I got him.
我抓到他了
32X to CP. We're being fired upon!
32X向总部报告 我们被开枪射击！
An officer is down. I repeat, an officer is down. A trooper's been shot!
警员中枪，需要急救
Send some back...
快派支援...
So do you know why Queenan went into that building?
你知道为什么昆南要去那栋楼？
- No. - Well, a better question...
- 不知道 - 我有更好的问题问你
...is why the fuck were your guys following him?
为什么你的人跟踪他？
I told Internal Investigations to follow Captain Queenan.
我让内部调查组的人跟踪昆南的
- Why? - That's Internal Investigations' business.
- 为什么？ - 那是内部调查组的事
Fucking piece of shit!
狗娘养的!
- All right. - Hey, hey!
- 算了 - 嘿!
- Fucking bitch! - Let him go!
- 你这个混蛋! - 放开他!
Cocksucker! I don't have to fucking explain anything to anybody!
混蛋!我不用向任何人解释!
I can fucking investigate anybody I want to!
我可以调查任何人，想查谁就查谁
- Come on! - I don't give a fuck what you think!
- 来啊! - 我才在乎你怎么想!
I got reason to believe that Queenan got killed by his fucking undercover.
我有理由相信 昆南是被他自己的卧底杀害的
That's a fucking lie.
撒谎
He has fucking information in a locked file, as did Captain Queenan.
他的电脑里保存着很多加密档案 昆南队长的也是
I need access to those files.
我要那些档案
I forgot the password but if you come with me I'll give it to you.
我忘记密码了 有种你和我去车库，在那我就告诉你
- That's a fucking lie. - Nobody calls me a liar!
- 撒谎 - 你再说一次!
Shut up! Work with the tech guys to unlock those files.
闭嘴!让技术人员把那些档案解密
- Dignam, take a leave of absence. - Take a leave of what?
- 你暂时离职 - 你说让我什么？
Queenan is dead. I'm your boss now.
昆南死了，现在我是你的头
I don't care. I'd rather hand in my papers first.
我不管，我宁愿辞职
World needs plenty of bartenders. Two weeks with pay.
外面多得是酒吧服务生 给你两周带薪假
Good.
好极了
- Piece of shit. - Fuck off.
- 你这混蛋 - 去死
- I need those codes. - No.
- 我需要密码 - 不
You want those codes.
你想要密码
So where the fuck were you?
你他妈跑哪去了？
Well, boss told me to go home.
老板让我回家
Whatever. Maybe he did, maybe he didn't. But you werert at fucking home.
算了，他可能这么说了 不过你根本不在家
So where the fuck were you?
你去哪了？
I was at the grocery store with no signal, all right?
我在一家食品店，那里没信号
When I got the signal, I got the call.
有信号的时候，我才接到电话
What the fuck do you want from me? Was I there or was I not there?
你想怎么样？我不是去了吗?
Billy. Billy.
比利，比利
Yeah?
怎么了?
You know what I thought today?
知道我今天想什么吗？
What's that?
什么?
Who didn't show up today is the rat.
今天没出现的人,就是内鬼
Yeah?
是吗？
- So? - And you never been late in your life.
- 所以呢? - 你从来没有迟到过
When I called you...
我打给你的时候...
...I made a mistake.
我犯了个错误
I gave you the wrong address...
我给你的地址是错的
...but you showed up at the right one...
但你却在正确的地址出现了
...didn't you?
是不是？
Tell me why I didn't tell nobody, huh?
告诉我为什么这事我谁都没告诉?
Tell me why.
告诉我为什么
That cop was tough. We were excessive with the cop.
那警察是条硬汉 我们对他做的有点过分了
He's dead.
他死了
I'm going home.
我回家去了
- Your guys should not have done that. - One of us had to die.
- 你的人不该那么做 - 我们俩总要死一个
With me it tends to be the other guy.
所以自然是他先死了
But Queenan. Now I got no access.
现在昆南死了，我无从下手
You killed the guy who had the info. Dignam's gone. Forget about him.
你杀了那个知道所有信息的人 现在迪克曼也走了，别再提他了
- He resigned. - I don't give a fuck about Dignam.
- 他辞职了 - 我他妈才不在乎迪克曼
He put in his papers, Frank.
他交了辞呈，弗兰克
- He left. I don't know where he is. - Don't get your balls in an uproar, Collie.
- 他走了，我不知道他去哪了 - 迪克曼好对付，科林
That Irish pissant...
那家伙一心想抓住我
...he's so hot for me, we give him a whiff of my ass, he'll crawl right in it.
稍微放出点消息，他就会找上门来
Let's give him a whiff.
把他引出来吧
- I will. - Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
- 我会的 - 别担心，我会处理的
Sweetheart.
亲爱的
You're giving me a hard-on.
你让我兴奋起来了
Are you sure it's me?
你确定是因为我吗？
Not all that talk about whiffing and crawling up asses?
还是因为你刚才的电话？
Watch your fucking mouth.
你他妈的说话小心点
No. You watch it.
不，是你小心点
Let me straighten you out.
我来帮你爽一下
I tried to call you a few times.
我给你打过几次电话
I know.
我知道
Listen, I can't be a friend to you.
我不能当你朋友
I'm sorry.
对不起
Yeah...
恩...
...I know.
我知道
Yeah.
喂
You called this number on a dead guy's phone.
你用死人的手机打电话给我
Who are you?
你是谁?
So it is you.
是你啊
Well, thank God you're all right. We were very worried.
谢天谢地你没事 我们很担心你
Who are you?
你到底是谁？
This is Sergeant Sullivan.
我是苏利文警官
I'm taking over Queenars unit.
我现在接管昆南的部门
Let me talk to Dignam to confirm it.
我需要和迪克曼核实一下
Staff Sergeant Dignam...
迪克曼警官在离职...
...is on a leave of absence. He's very upset.
他现在很不稳定
We're all very upset.
我们大家都是
I think the best thing would be for you to come in.
你最好能过来一下
We need you to come in. Can you come in?
我们需要你过来，你能来吗?
We'll meet...
我们在...
Police confirm the body of the man found dead...
警方证实昨天下午在沼泽地带
...in the Fenway marshes yesterday...
发现男尸是德拉亨特
...is that of Timothy Delahunt, an undercover policeman for...
波士顿警局的卧底警员
...the city of Boston. This was the scene yesterday...
他的尸体昨天下午在沼泽地
...when Delahunt's body was found in the marshes near the Fenway.
附近的公路上被发现
As for who did this or why...
至于案件是谁人所为，作案动机为何
...that's something police are working on right now.
还在调查之中
- I don't believe it. - What can't you believe?
- 真是难以置信 - 你有什么不能相信的？
I spent all fucking night dragging the poor bastard in there.
我他妈花了一整夜把这混蛋弄到那去
Tell me how they found him so fast.
你说他们怎么这么快就找到了？
Somebody walking a fucking dog in three feet of mud?
就因为有人在3尺烂泥潭溜狗？
What kind of fucking size of dog is that?
那他妈狗是什么狗啊?
Must have been a big fucking dog, man.
肯定是只大狗
I spent all fucking night doing it, man.
我他妈花了整整一晚的时间
I'm embarrassed.
真是丢人啊
I still don't believe he was a cop. I don't believe it.
我还是不信他是个警察 我不信
The cops are saying he's a cop...
警察们说他是警察...
...so I won't look for the cop.
好让我认为他是警察
Are you soft, Fitz?
你听好
When I tell you to dump a body in the marsh...
我让你把尸体扔进沼泽
...you dump him in the marsh.
那你就乖乖的把尸体扔进沼泽
Not where some guy from John Hancock goes every Thursday...
而不是扔到一个每周四都会有人...
...to get a fucking blowjob!
固定去那做口交的地方！
Don't laugh!
别笑了!
This ain't reality TV!
这他妈不是电视真人秀！
Proceed.
出发吧
- What? - Yeah.
- 怎么了? - 喂
You got a tail. Two cars. Not very subtle.
有人跟踪你 两部车，跟着你并没有刻意躲避
They're not gonna be subtle from now on. That's what I've been trying to say.
从现在开始，他们不会再遮遮掩掩地了
So get rid of them.
那就把他们甩掉
There's no need for you to go yourself, Frank.
你没必要亲自去，弗兰克
Get rid of the fucking tail!
把他们给我甩掉!
All right.
好吧
Fucking rats. It's wearing me thin.
可恶的内鬼 我发誓要对付他们
Francis, it's a nation of fucking rats.
弗朗西斯，这个国家就是这样
Stop, stop. Pull them off Costello. There's no need to surveil him.
停下，停下 叫他们停下来，不用再监视了
- What are you saying? - I got it from an undercover.
- 你说什么呢？ - 我听卧底说卡斯特罗
He knows he's being followed. So let the UC take him in.
已经知道自己被跟踪了 那我们就交给卧底好了
- Undercover? - Queenars guy.
- 什么卧底？ - 昆南的那个卧底
He called when he found out Queenan died. I'm running him.
他得知昆南的死讯后给我打了电话 他现在和我联系
- You give him to me. - No, I can give you Costello's destination.
- 和你？你得把他交给我 - 我可以告诉你卡斯特罗要去哪
- You know where he's going? - Yes. And what he's doing.
- 你知道他要去哪？ - 是的，我还知道他要做什么
Get rid of the tail, get Special Ops on standby.
停止跟踪，叫大家随时待命
- We'll take this prick tonight. - Let's go. Now.
- 我们今晚就跟这个混蛋做个了结 - 我们行动吧
All units fall back.
所有人员撤回，所有人员撤回
It's the warehouse he owns over on Sheffield.
好了，在他设菲尔德的私人仓库里
He's gotta have a container or a truck or something there. Go.
那一定有集装箱或是卡车什么的 走,走
Load it.
装车
Frank, how do you know you don't have a tail, huh?
弗兰克，你怎么知道没人跟踪我们？
Were you not in the fucking car?
你他妈刚才在车里没听到吗？
Yeah, what if they took one off and they put another one on?
万一他们换了别的车跟踪我们呢？
Load.
装车
Go, go!
快来!
Come on, what are you waiting for?
你等什么呢？
Frank wants me to check the back. You go ahead.
弗兰克让我去查一下后面，你先走
- Watch your fucking back. - Move out! Go on!
- 看着你身后 - 我们走!
Cocksuckers.
妈的
Motherfucking shit!
混蛋!
Motherfucking...!
操....
Back the fuck up!
快增援!
They fucking shot me.
我他妈的中弹了
Get down!
蹲低!
Come on, fucking bastards!
来啊,混蛋!
Fuck it.
妈的
How the fuck did this happen?
怎么回事?
You're an FBI informant?
你是联邦调查局线人?
Are you fucking kidding me?
你他妈耍我吗？
Grow up.
成熟点吧
Of course I talk to the FBI.
我当然要跟联邦调查局有联系
Do they know who I am?
他们知道我的身份吗？
I never gave up anybody who wasrt going down anyway.
我从未出卖过任何人 除非那人本来就要被抓了
Nobody knows nothing.
谁都不知道
Frank.
弗兰克
Frank. Frank.
弗兰克,弗兰克
Do they know about me?
他们知道了我的事吗？
I know about you, Collie.
只有我知道你的事，科林
You know I'd never give you up.
你知道我永远不会出卖你的
- You're like a... - What? Like a son?
- 你就像... - 像你儿子？
To you? Is that what this is about?
就是这么回事吗？
All that murdering and fucking, and no sons.
杀人，胡搞了一辈子 最后连个儿子都没有
Fucking rat prick!
该死的，混蛋!
Frank?
弗兰克?
Yeah?
说话?
Who's this?
你是谁？
Gwen?
格温?
Where the hell's Frank?
弗兰克在哪儿？
Frank got shot.
弗兰克中枪了
Gwen, we lost Frank.
格温，弗兰克死了
I got him!
我打死他了!
I got Costello here!
卡斯特罗在这儿!
Hey, good job, sarge.
恭喜，干的好
No, it's...
不，只是...
For you.
给你的
- Thank you. - No. Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 不，谢谢你！
He's been waiting here a long time for you.
他在那等你很久了
How'd you get him without the files?
你怎么找到他的？
Caller ID on Queenars phone.
用昆南的手机联系上他的
You know that guy?
你认识他吗？
Yeah. We were classmates in the academy together.
是，我们在警校是同学
Good to see you, trooper.
很高兴见到你，警官
- Yeah. - Colin Sullivan. We spoke on the phone.
- 你好 - 我是科林 苏利文,我们在电话里聊过
- So.
- 没错 - 那么
Now, how long were you undercover?
你做卧底多久了？
Long time.
很久，很久了
- Long fucking time. - Yeah. Yeah.
- 真得很久了 - 当然
Well, I can't even tell you the debt...
我无法表达我们有多感谢你...
I just want you to know I'll be recommending you for the Medal of Merit.
我会推荐你荣誉奖章的
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
- 哦，是吗？ - 是的
That's kind of like a gold star around here, huh?
听上去很诱人啊
It's the highest honor we got.
这是我们的最高荣誉
Look, I just want my identity back, all right?
我只想要恢复我的身份
- That's all. - All right.
- 好吗 - 可以
- I understand. You wanna be a cop again. - No, no.
- 我知道，你想重新做个警察 - 不
Being a cop's not an identity. I want my identity back.
不，当警察并不是我的身份 我要我自己的身份
Check your computer. Go on. You'll have to excuse my behavior.
查一下你的电脑 把我之前的罪行都删除
My only contact in the last six months has been a police shrink.
我过去六个月来唯一打过交道的 只有一个心理医生
How's that working for you?
怎么样?
Is it helpful?
辅导有效果吗？
What are you gonna do about Costello's rat in this building?
你想怎么处理 卡斯特罗安插在这里的内鬼呢？
- I'm gonna find the prick. - Yeah.
- 我会找到他的 - 是吗
I'm gonna find him, I'm gonna arrest him.
我会找到他，并且逮捕他的
- Good. - Anything you can do to help me...
- 好 - 你要尽力帮我
You know, I mean, did Frank ever mention a name...? You know, anything.
弗兰克近期有没有提到什么人 或者联系什么人？
Someone he was in contact with. Anything you can give me.
把你知道的都告诉我
I'm all done being a cop, all right?
我做警察已经当够了
I just want my money and I wanna go home.
把钱给我，我想回家
All right. That'll be the best thing for everybody.
好的，这样对大家都好
Fair enough.
非常合理
I just, I can't get into your file unless I have your password.
只是我打不开你的档案 除非告诉我你的密码
It's my name.
密码就是我的名字
William Costigan Jr.
小威廉・科斯提根
They gave it to me in case I had to explain myself to someone like you.
他告诉我就是怕有朝一日 我需要向你这样的人解释我的身份
It's your name.
你的名字
All right.
好的
Fucking unreal, that... Well, makes a lot of sense.
那倒也很合理
Listen, Bill, I gotta run this in the other room.
比尔，我到隔壁去处理这个
This computer's getting all frigging blooey on me.
这台电脑对我很不友好
Give me two minutes. I'll have you out of here in no time.
等我2分钟，我马上就帮你解决好
All right, everything checks out, so let's get you paid.
好的，都办好了 现在把薪水给你
I know.
我知道，我知道
I know. I'm not... I'm not here for that, okay?
我不是为那事来的
I'm not.
我不是
Listen. I've gotta give you something.
我得交给你点东西
Something I need you to keep.
你要替我保存好
For me.
为我
Okay?
好吗?
- What is it? - This is for you to hold. Only you.
- 什么东西？ - 你帮我保管，只有你
You open this if something happens to me or if I call you and I tell you to open it.
如果我有什么不测 或是我让你打开你才能打开
You're the only person I can trust, all right?
你是我唯一可以相信的人
Please.
求你了
- All right. - Look, I'm sorry to even...
- 好的 - 抱歉...
I'm sorry to even show up here like this, you know?
抱歉，我以这种方式现身
L... There's just no one else I could give it to.
只是我不知道还能把这个交给谁
There's no one else.
只有你
- I'm really sorry. - I...
- 抱歉 - 我...
You know, I have...
我有...
- Whatever you have to say...
- 不管你想说什么...
...think about it real hard, all right?
请三思，好吗?
If you still wanna tell me, you tell me in two weeks, okay?
如果你还想说 两周之后再告诉我，好吗?
I was dreaming I was dead.
我刚才梦到我死了
Death is hard. Life is much easier.
死亡是很痛苦的 活着更容易些
- What's this? - Open it.
- 这是什么？ - 打开看看
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的？ - 真的
Really?
真的?
Yeah.
真的
And they say that this little speck...
他们说那个小点是
...is a penis.
小鸡鸡
It's a boy.
哇，是个男孩
Yeah, well, one usually follows the other.
有其父必有其子
Can you still...?
那你还能...?
I hope I won't have to remind you...
我希望不用再提醒你
...that if you don't find this cheese-eating rat bastard in your department...
如果你不找出安插在我这的内鬼
...you can assume it won't be me who pays for it.
最先倒霉的可不是我
Now, why would you have to remind me of that?
何必一再提醒我这点？
Would l...? Would I be any good at what I do if I didn't fucking already know that?
难道这对我现在的工作有任何帮助吗？
Frank, you gotta trust me. I can get the rat.
弗兰克，你得相信我
You just gotta let me do it my way, Frank.
好吗？相信我，弗兰克
Just let me do it. Let me do what I do.
你得让我放手去干
Hey, it fucking involves lying and I'm pretty fucking good at that. Right?
要是需要撒谎的话 你知道我他妈很在行的
What?
怎么了?
- We got a cop in my crew. - Yeah, I know.
- 我这里混进了个警察 - 我知道
- I'm kind of getting that feeling too. - He's one of yours. Inside.
- 我也感觉到了 - 是你们的人
- You seen anything? - Frank.
- 发现什么了吗？ - 弗兰克
I got no access to Queenars undercover files. He and Dignam run the snitches.
弗兰克，我没有权限查看卧底档案 昆南和...
- I'm doing my... - You know what, I thought I was the liar.
知道吗?我还以为我才是骗子
Hey, I can explain that!
嘿，我可以解释的！
Costello recorded everything.
卡斯特罗把所有的东西都录了下来
He put all the tapes in a box and kept them with his lawyer. That was his insurance.
为了保险起见 他把所有的带子都放进一个小盒 交给他的律师保管
His lawyer came to me.
律师找了我
Imagine that, you rat fuck.
想像下，你这死内鬼
Costello trusted me more than anyone.
卡斯特罗最信任的是我
Sound quality good enough? Because I was a little worried.
录音的音质足够好? 开始我还有点担心
- What do you want? - I told you I want my identity back...
- 你想要什么？ - 我告诉过你我要自己的身份
...you two-faced faggot.
你这两面派
- All right, where are you? - Three o'clock. Where Queenan died.
- 你在哪? - 三点钟，昆南死的地方
You keep your cell on.
开着手机
Open the door.
开门
Open... Didrt we already talk about this?
开...我们不是已经谈过了吗？
This is my job.
这是我的工作
- Freeze! Get your fucking hands up! - Hey!
- 别动！举起手！ - 嘿!
Put the fucking gun down!
嘿，把枪放下！
Put the gun down, all right? I came here to talk some sense into you.
把枪放下！我来是...
- Hands! - Just act professional.
- 手! - 好的，专业点
- I can get you your money. - What did you say?
- 我给你钱 - 你说什么？
- You didn't come here to talk, all right?
- 我可以给你钱 - 你来这儿不是和来谈判的
- You came here to get arrested. - You got fucking tapes? Of what?
- 你是来被捕的 - 你有盘狗屁录音又怎么样？
Costello was my informant. I was a rat? Fuck you! Prove it.
卡斯特罗是我的线人 我是卧底?去你妈的，你能证明吗？
He was working for me. He was my informant.
他为我工作，他是我的线人
Shut your fucking mouth. Come on, get up!
闭嘴，起来
What is this, a citizers arrest? Blow me, all right?
这算什么? 你逮捕警察吗？ 开枪啊?
Only one of us is a cop here, Bill. You understand that, Bill?
我们两个只有一个是警察，比尔 你知道吗，比尔？
- No one knows you. - Shut the fuck up!
- 没人知道... - 闭上你的臭嘴!
I'm a sergeant in the Massachusetts State Police. Who the fuck are you?
我是麻萨诸塞州警官 你他妈算什么？
- I erased you! - You erased me, huh?
- 我把你的档案都删了！ - 你把我的档案删了？
Yeah, go ahead, shoot a cop, Einstein. Watch what happens.
继续呀！干掉警察啊！ 看看会怎么样
This bullet would go right through your fucking head!
怎么样？我会打爆你的头!
- Watch what happens! - What, so you can get the parade, huh?
- 再然后呢？ - 葬礼游行，洗礼什么的？
The bagpipes and bullshit? Fuck you! Fuck you, I'm fucking arresting you!
你这混蛋，我他妈要逮捕你!
- That's the stupidest thing you could do. - Shut the fuck up!
- 你要那么做就太他妈蠢了 - 闭嘴!
I could give a fuck if the charges don't stick.
我他妈不管什么罪名
I'm still fucking arresting you.
我就他妈就要逮捕你
Get up.
起来
Drop your weapon and step away from Sergeant Sullivan.
放下武器！ 放开苏利文警官！
I called you. You specifically. Look:
是我打电话给你的 只打给你了
You know who I am. I'm not gonna shoot. I told you to meet me downstairs.
我知道我的，我不会开枪 我告诉过你在楼下见我
Put your weapon on the deck and step away from Sergeant Sullivan!
放下武器！ 放开苏利文警官!
Where's Dignam? I told you to bring Dignam!
迪克曼在哪？ 我告诉过你带迪克曼来！
Shoot this motherfucker! Would you fucking shoot!
开枪！打他！
- Drop your weapon. We'll discuss it. - Look, he's Costello's rat, all right?
- 把枪放在地上！之后我们再谈 - 听着，苏利文是内鬼！
I got boxes of tapes! Evidence! Other documents proving it!
我有录音，文件 所有的证据都能证明！
Maybe you do.
也许你有
But right now I need you to drop the weapon!
但现在你要放下武器
I have evidence cold-linking this prick to Costello, all right?
我告诉过你，我有证据证明 他就是卡斯特罗的内鬼
- Would you shoot this fucking prick! - You know who I am.
- 干掉这个疯子！ - 你知道我是谁
- Shoot this fucking prick.
- 开枪射他
I'm taking him downstairs now.
现在我要把他带到楼下去
You know who I am.
你知道我是谁
Shut up.
闭嘴
I can't wait to see you explain this to a Suffolk County jury...
我真是迫不及待得想看 你怎么和陪审团解释这一切
...you fucking cocksucker.
你这傻x
This is gonna be fucking fun.
这他妈好一定会很好玩
Just fucking kill me.
杀了我吧
I am killing you.
我会的
Did you think you were the only one he had on the inside?
你觉得你是唯一一个内鬼？
Costello was gonna sell us to the FBI.
卡斯特罗打算把我们出卖给联邦调查局的
It's you and me now, you understand?
我们现在在一条船上，你明白吗？
We gotta take care of each other, you understand?
我们要互相照顾，你明白吗？
Give me that.
给我
I attempted to subdue Trooper Barrigan...
我在试图制服北芮根时...
...at which time he drew down on me, and I was able to squeeze off one shot...
他向我开了枪 我奋力开了一枪
...and strike him in the head.
开枪击中他的头部
At that time I immediately checked the vitals...
之后我立即检查科斯提根...
...on both Troopers Brown and Costigan...
和布朗两名州警的呼吸心跳
...and discovered that they had expired.
发现他们已经死亡了
I just wanna go on record.
请把这个也记录下来
I'm recommending William Costigan for the Medal of Merit.
我推荐威廉 科斯提根 作为荣誉勋章候选人
- Eternal rest grant unto him, O Lord. - Ready?
- 愿他得到永远的安息 - 准备好了吗?
- And let perpetual light shine upon him. - Fold.
- 愿永恒之光照耀其身 - 折
May he rest in peace. Amen.
让他安息吧,阿门
May his soul and the souls...
愿忠实逝者的灵魂伴随主的慈悲...
...of all the faithful departed, through the mercy of God, rest in peace.
安息
Amen.
阿门
Detail. Half left. Face.
准备，执礼
Prepare to fire.
准备鸣枪
Fire.
鸣枪！
Prepare to fire. Fire.
准备鸣枪，鸣枪！
Detail. Half right. Face.
礼毕
I'll catch up with you guys.
我一会来找你们
What about the baby?
孩子怎么样了？
Hi, pup.
狗狗
Okay.
开枪吧